[music]
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat.
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
[clears throat]
>> Hello, good evening and welcome to the
Askab show episode 320. I hope you're
all doing great. Today I'm going to take
questions that you have asked in the
comments and I'm going to discuss
geopolitics as well as history. Maybe
take a mixture of reasonably equal
amounts of both uh questions from both
topics. I'll take about 20 questions
today and then I'll take some questions
from the live chat or super chat and uh
that shall be the agenda for this live
stream. But before we start, let us see
who all is there on the live chat.
Minimalist Maverick Sajjit Gokul has
become a new member. Thank you so much
Sajjit Gokul and welcome to the
channel's membership. I really
appreciate that. Geopolitical [snorts]
Dubai is here from Indor Mac 4J1U.
Uh Aush Singh is here. Pranamar G Rocky
Gaming good evening Jind realmir Putin
Jam G Nirvana Shanks Kodi Jar Nirvana
Shanksan Swami0709
Mr. Jam Radhir Radi rogue gamer
Manhattan real bhutin dwit ashwini air
is manticor hello abishek shukla live
says 500% tariffs are coming we'll see
looks like that could be humanity
survives Ramnam Albert Davis good
evening sir Anand Anandam S2825 hello
lazy gamer hello Swami is here from
Jaipur Swami0709
says, "Am I going to sing or something?"
Well, I am not going to sing. [laughter]
Uh, Suganta BKS, namaste. Crazy brain,
hello, good to see you. Crazy brain. Mr.
Gap Patel, good evening. Good evening
from Otawa. Random Skull, hello Kerkar,
hello, good to see you. Ramshes
7757. Lazy Gamer. Ramsh says, "Please
continue the series off." Off off. Okay.
Jay Guman is here and it is morning in
Quebec. Mojour miss you Jay Guman. Hitan
Shua good evening from Gujarat. Good
good evening to you. Arismantic Himmanu
Rajit from Chennai. Ram Ram Manisharu
namaste. Namaste. Vikash PJ good evening
online Mahadev bro. Uh advocate Sam
Achara. Hello. Who else do we have? Adit
Ashini Crazy Brains. Um
Ram Shreas Abishaka live is here from
Kpur and Shul Takur Radhira Mahita
Bushetti good evening ma'am good to have
you Rohit is here from Chennai Hidar Pab
hello Swami have I seen once upon a time
in the west I'm sure I have yes uh
Ragavir Singh Wir once again Vikash PJ
Priyanka Priyanka Javalia hello namaste
good to have you ma'am good to see you
John M funk hello sir namaste to you as
well. Good to have you. Adwit Ashwari
Jaguan. Um, who else do we have? Moan
Sharma is here from Jaipur. Monkey Luffy
Hoola. PG is here from Germany. Uh, Moan
Sharma from Jaipur. Manhattan. I6W.
Kavish Razap.
Asalamu alaikum to you as well. Rocky
Gaming from Rajasthan. Uh, he buati.
Hello. Um Ramsh says please continue the
understanding America series. Well there
seems to be significant demand for that.
I may have to take it very seriously.
Okay I hear you noted partapati is here
from J uh from Japan not Jaipun Jaipur
Japan. Uh Mat from Pune and Orishnik
strikes
Manhattan says orishnik strikes did not
do much well they were not designed to
do a lot of damage. They did not
possibly have warheads. Ornic missiles
are IRBMs, intercontinental range
ballistic missiles
>> and they are actually designed to
they're supposed to carry
the big stuff nuclear warheads but those
were used to hit a gas facility in
western Ukraine.
Um so the objective was not to cause
devastation. The objective was to
deprive Ukraine of of its winter
reserves of gas because of the strikes
that Ukraine did on and attempted to
take the life of President Putin. That
sort of thing. So, you know, there's
going to be action reaction. That's how
it goes. Um,
Sat Satyam Ja is here from Vladim.
Vladivosto. Well, that's a good place to
be in. Very cool, I suppose. And okay,
General Subutai is here from Mongolia.
All right.
Okay. Okay. Okay. So, uh let us now
stop.
U I'm going to
say from the Philippines. Okay. So,
let's take the questions now. Okay. I
will not be able to greet you all
individually as you know. But uh let's
let's get going with the questions. What
questions do we have today? Let us
begin.
Okay. Uh this is from Rushabare. Given
the recent developments in Venezuela,
how do you see the role of bricks ahead?
Recently there was news that a Russian
tanker was seized in the Atlantic.
Moreover, Iran, one of the top suppliers
of oil to China is facing crisis. Oh
yeah, they are facing a crisis. So what
op options do they have now? Could
Russia now escalate the war in Ukraine?
And can China now make a move on Taiwan
or does it face the risk of being
encircled? And how does this impact
India and our neighborhood? And what
cards do we have now? Okay, a lot
happening. A lot happening. See, first
of all, the US last year, just a couple
of months ago, came up with uh uh this
national security strategy, this new
document in which they have
operationalized
a 21st century version of the Monroe
Doctrine. The Monro Doctrine was an old
US foreign policy from 1823 which said
that the US will no longer allow any
external non-hemismic power to interfere
in the Americas, North America or South
America. No European power, no other
power will be allowed to interfere. Only
the US will be allowed to be the sole
hedgeman and the global super cop in the
Americas. That's the old 1823
uh Monro doctrine. Now there is a Trump
corollary to that that's been added on
top of it. It says that that not only
will external non-hemismic powers not be
allowed to operate and and interfere in
the Americas but even local regional
actors such as governments that may not
be aligned with the US objectives or US
interests or cartels or whatever even
those will not be allowed to operate and
the US will go after any of them to hell
with international law and that's what
the US is doing now. So the Americans
have now see we know they did a regime
change in Venezuela. They they kidnapped
they abducted the president of
Venezuela, Mr. Maduro and his wife who
are now in prison in the US awaiting
some sort of trial. Um and the the
Americans have said that Venezuela will
now operate as per American demands. All
the oil that Venezuela sells will be
sold through the United States. So it's
it's like the good old good old East
India Company situation. Whatever India
exported while under British occupation
was exported to Britain or through
Britain and all the profits were taken
by the British with a little bit
trickling back to India just to kind of
stay stay semi-conscious that sort of
thing. So that's the East India Company
colonial policy that which is exactly
what the US is now operationalizing in
Venezuela. And to make this happen, if
you want to ensure if you are the United
States and you want to make sure that
Venezuela's oil only passes through
American channels and American hands,
whether it's sold to the US or to third
parties, it has to be sold through the
US. That's how the US controls
everything. Now if you have tankers, oil
tankers or other vessels that are that
are carrying the flags of other nations
like Russia for example or China or
whatever and they come to Venezuela and
take oil the Americans will not allow
that. If this happens then the American
Monro doctrine and Trump corally
corollary goes for a toss and it loses
credibility. So the that's why the US
has gone ahead and seized this Russian
tanker. I think it was not carrying any
oil. Was it carrying something else? We
don't know. It's not been declared. But
the Americans went ahead and boarded the
vessel and captured the vessel and its
crew. There's a couple of Indians on
board. The there's a bunch of Ukrainian
citizens and some a couple of Russian
citizens also maybe. Uh that sort of
situation is there right now. So what's
the status of the crew? The vessel. It's
it's it's a work in process right now.
We don't quite know exactly what the
situation is. Right. So the last we know
is that the Americans boarded and
captured the vessel and its crew. Um now
you say rightfully that Iran is facing a
crisis. You know there's tremendous
demonstrations and whatnot in Iran. The
people I suppose have been have been fed
up of the Islamic regime regime in Iran.
I think that's that's an organic
sentiment that comes up from the ground
level. It's not astroturfed. It's not
manufactured. I'm sure there'll be some
Iranians
who will be aligned with the Islamic
regime, but I I think it's pretty clear
that the the majority of the people uh
aren't aligned with the Islamic regime
in Iran and they seek a change and
that's that's that makes Iran fertile
ground for a US regime change operation
or US-led regime change operation and it
it do dubtales perfectly with US
interests in the region. Right? So if
the Americans take Persia, take take
Iran, okay, the effect of regime change
and bring back the son of the sha or
whatever. Yeah. Then you will have Iran,
this big powerful nation in West Asia
just west of the subcontinent, it will
now become a US asset. It will become
operationalized as as a US asset. Right?
And if that happens, then the Americans
control essentially most of the oil
supply, energy supply in the world.
Venezuela 20% of oil reserves. Okay.
[snorts]
Uh we know that the Venezuelan oil is is
special oil. It's heavy oil. It's sour
oil. There's only three or four
refineries in the world that can process
that, including one in India, right? But
still, it's 20% of the world's oil
reserves, proven oil reserves. Now, if
you take Iran, the Americans already
control Iraq. They control the UAE.
They, you could say, control Saudi
Arabia to a large extent, right? The
Saudis can't do much against the US.
Then if they control Iran as well
then that becomes a huge problem for a
nation like China which then becomes
very dependent on Russia because even
other nations like Angola, Nigeria,
whatsoever all these nations are also
alligned with the US. So if if the
Americans take Iran then they can
essentially clamp down on China's energy
supply on demand and make China
completely dependent on Russia.
Right? So and and We are also seeing
other movements in the region. For
example, Somali land is being recognized
now. It's been recognized by Israel. The
UAE has also defacto recognized Somali
land. So that becomes a piece of the
puzzle that the Americans can now put in
their kitty because they can now start
dominating the Gulf of Adan the straight
the straight of Babal Mandab region.
They can choke off all the u goods
supplies etc. That's that that move into
China. We Indians talk about blockading
Malaka. The Americans will blockade
Babal Mand and Hormuz. Why blockade
Mala? The Americans think 20 steps
ahead. So
the Americans are essentially putting
the pieces
aligning the pieces in the geopolitical
chessboard such that they can to China,
start the process of choke of of being
in a position to choke off China on
demand if whenever required. Right.
And um could Russia now escalate the war
in Ukraine? Well, I suppose they could.
They are in a position to do that. They
have the the resources, the the the
military capabilities, etc. And there
there is some escalation of the war in
Ukraine. The Russians uh just a few
hours ago launched a series of missile
strikes in western Ukraine. They took
out a big uh
gas reservoir
which uh supplies Ukraine with energy in
winter. Winter is here and Ukraine is
now is going to lose that energy. Right.
So the Russians used ornik uh IRBMs
intern intercontinental I'm sorry
intermediate range ballistic missiles to
strike at this uh gas reservoir or plant
or whatever it was. And the Orishnik
apparently the warheads did not contain
any any any explosive charges but they
were sufficient to devastate the thing
the the oil res the gas depot. That's
what it looks like. It's it's still to
be asserted and verified. Right. Uh so
that's the situation right now. Could
Russia make could Russia escalate the
war in Ukraine? Possibly. So the
Russians are the Americans are also
bringing in legislation that could uh
target Russia with 500% tariffs and
impose secondary tariffs on nations like
India, Brazil etc. China 500% tariffs on
on us. Yeah. So that will further u have
and the objective is to devastate the
Russian economy and to prevent other
nations from purchasing Russian oil
which is one of the major things that
the Russian economy depends on. Right?
So the Americans are are acting. See,
there are nations that talk. There are
nations that act. The Americans act.
Okay. Can China now make a move on
Taiwan? Well, I suppose they can, but
they will then that will the Americans
will turn Taiwan into China's Ukraine,
right? It'll start bleeding the Chinese
economy.
You see,
you see who's the most powerful nation
in the world. I've been saying this for
the longest time. China is not a
superpower. Not even not even close to
being a superpower. The only nation
close to being a superpower is Russia.
Let me put something on
the screen.
This is my power index of the most
powerful nations. This was calculated
last year. I will recalculate it this
for this year. I mean this was for 2024.
Not not much much has changed. So the
most powerful nation in the world is the
USA with a hard power score of 93.
Next is Russia with a hard power score
of 54. Russia at least fights. China
doesn't fight. It hides behind other
nations. China.
China hides behind Russia. China doesn't
dare fight the US. The Russians fight.
The Russians dare to fight. You can see
the difference between China and Russia.
So here we have Russia at number two.
The American hard power score is 93.
Russia's hard power score is 54. 54.
China has a hard power score of 15. and
India has 4.9. These are the four
nations that matter. Israel has a hard
power score of 0.62. But actually um
this is just a row hard power score.
Actually, Israel is one of the five
sovereign nations in the world. Only
five sovereign nations in the world
exist. I'm going to have to recalculate
the stuff for the year 2026.
Okay. Um yeah. So, Israel actually
should have a sovereignty score of over
one. So, that's the situation. Now, how
does this impact India? It's going to
impact India in a variety of ways. If
the Americans bring in their legislation
to impose 500%, you know, secondary
tariffs on India, that's going to
devastate the India US trade
relationship. Yeah. $120 billion or so.
It's the trade relationship that will
devastate any prospect of Indian exports
going to the US, right? It's going to be
a big setback for the Indian economy. I
wonder what it does to the Indian IT
sector. We I'm not sure we've looked
into that. Um and it's going to be a
huge leverage that the US has over India
to align India forcibly arm twist India
into forcibly aligning with American uh
policies, objectives and interests.
Essentially the US seeks to vasalize
India. If that happens, if that
succeeds, well then it's back to the
good old East India Company days for
India, right? So it it affects our
neighborhood also. Right? So that's the
situation right now overall. Now let's
discuss the next question. [snorts]
Okay. A couple of questions. One is by
Brianka Shaker Biswas and one is by real
Vladimir Putin. Do the unusually smooth
US dealings with Deli Rodriguez point to
a covert US Venezuela secret pact,
Maduro's swift capture, fast oil deals
and her brother's previous involvement.
Why did the US intervention in
Venezuela? Why was it so easy for the
US? Neither China nor Russia came to
save Venezuela. Even Venezuela didn't
resist. Chinese and Russian defense
systems failed. I think there may have
been some agreement, some back room deal
with Venezuela. The go government of
Venezuela and the US and the US
Venezuelan president would have agreed
with it in fear of US military. What's
my opinion? Okay. See, we what do we
know for sure? The Americans were able
to smoothly execute their military
operation in Venezuela, the regime
operation. They came in, they killed a
bunch of guys, Cubans, they abducted
Maduro and his wife and they left and
they left and and and they they kept
everything else intact. So when the
American helicopters and aircraft were
flying over Karakas, the city of
Karakas,
what resistance did Venezuela's armed
forces give? Essentially zero. There's
only one known launch of an of a
surfaceto-air missile, manpad missile
from the ground in Venezuela in Karakas.
One guy did his job. I wonder what was
done to him. I don't think I I doubt if
if that person is alive today right now.
So, one Venezuelan person, military
personnel launched a manpad missile and
that was it. There was no other
resistance. the Chinese and Russian
defense systems failed. I'm not sure
they failed. I don't think they were
operationalized. And if they were
operationalized, I mean, the radars must
have captured the American aircraft
coming in, you know, rotary aircraft and
fixed wing aircraft, whatever, they
would have seen that. Uh, but the
Venezuelans have the S300 system, which
is the older brother of the S400 and
500, right? The S300 is a reasonably
capable system. Why was it not used?
Why was there no AC fire, anti-aircraft
gunfire from the ground? Nothing.
Right? So, it's not that the Chinese and
Russian defense systems failed. It's
that the military chose not to use any
of that. Why did the military not use
any of the assets, the pretty powerful
assets they have? They they have
Sukcoys. They have much more. They use
nothing. Why is that? probably there was
a backdoor deal.
Okay, some kind of inside job maybe.
See, from the American perspective, what
was their objective? To capture Maduro
and to send a message to everybody in
the region, including the Venezuelan
government. So, the best way to achieve
this is without really fighting. The
best way to achieve this is by bribing
the key people. Maybe key people perhaps
in the Venezuelan government and maybe
key people perhaps in the Venezuelan
military. You give you bribe them. You
tell them to stand down when the
operation happens. Stand down. Stay
away. Nothing will happen to you. Okay?
And those who resist will be wiped out.
So when so Mr. Maduro had this personal
guard, personal bodyguard who are all
Cubans. Those were all apparently it's
it's being said that they were all
executed in cold blood.
So it's not that these defense systems
failed. most likely key members of the
government or
military or maybe both would have been
bribed by the Americans. So you achieve
your objectives without facing any real
danger. That's what the Americans did.
And from their perspective, it makes
sense. Why take a risk? Why take risks
where multiple aircraft could be hit,
targeted? The Americans don't take such
risks in Yemen, do they?
the Americans don't take such risks of
flying their aircraft, helicopters, etc.
over Yemen
but they did that in Venezuela. So
because they clearly were sure that that
no action will be taken against them. So
uh there could have been some kind of
agreement some kind of bribery deal or
something. Yeah. Is Madame Deli
Rodriguez involved in this? I can't say
for sure. Maybe maybe not. Maybe she's
not. Maybe somebody else may be
involved. Maybe somebody else was bought
out. Maybe you don't need to involve the
government. Maybe you just need to bribe
the armed forces because the armed
forces are the defenders of the country.
Just bribe the key members in the armed
forces. They'll ask their guys to stand
down. Then the government is powerless.
That also is a possibility. Uh so that's
the situation,
right? We don't know exactly what
happened, what went down, but the
Americans were able to achieve their
objectives without any damage, without
any casualties, which can only be
guaranteed if you can if you have bribed
the defenders.
That's what's happened.
Right. Next,
Singh says, "US is taking out its
anti-nations, its adversarial nations
with no difficulty whatsoever, while
China and Russia are just giving
statements. If it continues like this,
China and Russia will soon be allyless.
They will have no allies. Is this the
end end plan of the US? Maybe tackle
them separately."
You see my dear friends all that really
matters in the world of geopolitics and
in the world real world is hard power.
You have all these Indian analysts who
have been claiming China is a
superpower, Russia is this, China is
most more powerful than Russia and so
on. What is China doing? What action has
China taken? It's given out some stern
statements. Karinda like you say in
India that's all China has been able to
do. Even the Russians have not been able
to safeguard their their vessel that was
recently boarded and captured by the
Americans. The Americans have
essentially it's a slap in the face of
Russia. Humiliation. Go on, do what you
can. We tried assassinating your
President Putin. Now we are taking your
vessel in the Atlantic.
What can you do? What can you do? Show
us what you can do. That's what the
Americans saying. That is hard power.
the Americans can act with impunity
wherever they want in the world. So once
again, let me put this on the screen.
These are 24 2024 rankings, but they are
still valid today. The US is the sole
superpower with a hard power score of
93.32.
Russia is like half of the US in terms
of hard power, 54, slightly more than
half. And China is nowhere next to them,
15.23. And India, India is 4.91. If you
see these hard power scores, the US has
overwhelming
superiority over Russia or China. And
let's not even talk about India here.
China is overwhelming overwhelmingly
stronger than India, right?
So please understand these events
hopefully have shown you that all this
talk of China being a superpower, it's a
joke.
There's only one superpower and they are
now acting like a super superpower.
They're stampeding through the through
the through the jungle, right?
So what's the um end goal of the US?
What's the end plan? The end plan is to
first of all look we discussed the the
Monroe doctrine and the Trump corollary,
right? And people have been saying that
this the Americans are retreating into
hemispheric defense. They will only
defend their hemisphere now and they
will leave the rest to China. Do you
really think that's what the Americans
will do? It's hemisphere first, not
hemisphere only. So the US is now not
going to allow anybody to put even a
foot wrong in the western hemisphere.
The moment somebody does that to hell
with international law, they'll go and
grab the whistle or whatever. They'll do
whatever they want. This is now naked
imperial power
that's being shown to you and that's how
it's going to continue.
Okay? So the Western Hemisphere, the US
will rule it. Nobody dares interfere and
nobody can. Nobody has the strength, the
power to do it. In the eastern
hemisphere, the Americans will interfere
everywhere.
Okay? They will most likely go after
Iran. Now,
the conditions are ripe on the streets
of of of Iran in the major cities,
Thran, Mashad, wherever. People are sick
and tired of the of the the regime of
the ayatas. The people of Iran probably
do not want to be ruled by by the
moolas. They want uh freedom. They want
democracy. Whatever. The Americans will
give them exactly what they want and
they'll portray that as a liberation. So
Iran,
it's it may be a matter of hours or days
or weeks.
It's it's going to change very rapidly
in Iran.
Okay. I get the get the feeling Iran is
going to fall to the Americans soon.
maybe a combination of America and
Israel together. Uh that's what it looks
like. Now let's say the Americans do
that and effect a regime change in Iran.
So Iran is now then if that happens Iran
becomes a US asset. So in West Asia,
Iran is a US asset. All the Gulf nations
are US assets. Yemen can be dealt with
once this is done. Right? Pakistan is a
US asset. It's in the subcontinent.
Yeah, Iran is the bridge between the
subcontinent and West Asia. So, Pakistan
is a US asset. Iran is a US asset. I
mean, so what is left? So, Iran is one
of the major uh players in the in the
Russia China access, right? It's Russia,
it's China, it's Iran, it's North Korea.
Maybe the Yemen is the Yemen is rather
insignificant without Iranian support.
So if Iran is taken out, the Chinese
lose about 15 20% of their oil supply,
energy supply and they lose a big asset
and the Iranians are also supplying
Russia with drones and whatnot. The
Russians lose that. It's a huge setback
for both China and Russia. So at the end
of the day, what's the end goal of the
US? The end goal of the US is to
vasalize everybody including India and
then deal with China and Russia only.
That's the end goal. And that the
Americans have calculated they will win.
If they play the cards right, China is
easier. Russia is not. But if Russia is
completely isolated, what do they do? So
that is the game. That's the game that's
being played.
See, the US has overwhelming superiority
in in hard power.
It's not like the 20th century cold war
where the US and USSR kind of equals in
terms of hard power. kind of roughly
it's not the case right only saving
grace is its massive arsenal of nuclear
weapons then you can deal with a nation
like Russia in other ways I suppose
creative ways in China what hard power
do they have they have economic might
they have the industrial base but do
they have the sharp edge that the
Americans and Russians have the Chinese
don't have it they are untested in war
China and Russia under tremendous
pressure and so is India by the
Brazil
Abijit Chabda Light says, "Is it true
that having nukes can save you from a
potential US invasion?"
Look, to be a sovereign nation,
a necessary condition today is nuclear
weapons. So unless you have nuclear
weapons, you're not going to be
sovereign today. That's the deal. It's a
having nuclear weapons is a necessary
condition. But is it sufficient to have
nuclear weapons? Take the case of the
United Kingdom. The United Kingdom has
nuclear warheads that they have made on
with their own hands.
But those nuclear warheads
are mated to American missiles.
Okay. So if the UK wants to dispatch a
nuclear warhead somewhere that nuclear
warhead will not go anywhere unless the
American missile takes the nuclear
warhead there. And who controls the
American missiles? Do you think the
prime minister of the UK controls the
American missiles? Do you think so? I
guarantee you that's not the case.
Whoever is the current prime minister of
the UK, who is it right now? Kir
Starmer, that that fellow, he doesn't
control those nuclear missiles. That big
red button doesn't sit in London. It
sits it sits in Washington. So the UK's
nuclear deterrent is actually American
de facto American nuclear deterrent. So
the UK has nukes,
but the nukes aren't in its control.
So if if the Americans tomorrow morning
decide to send 10,000 troops to London,
what will the UK do? Absolutely nothing.
It has nuclear weapons. Aha. Big haha.
Take the case of Ukraine.
The USSR broke up in 1991 or
thereabouts, right? And one of the
nations that emerged out of the break up
of the USSR was Ukraine.
And when the UK when Ukraine was part of
the USSR, they had nuclear weapons on
their territory. So when the nation
broke up this free independent Ukraine
that emerged, it had nuclear weapons on
its territory which it controlled.
And then Russia and the US promised
Ukraine, you know what? We're going to
guarantee your peace, security, blah
blah blah blah blah. You give up your
nuclear weapons. Give give them up to
Russia. We will guarantee your security.
So the Ukrainians said, "Okay, thank God
somebody is guaranteeing our security."
The promise, thank God we have this
promise in words. So here, take our
nukes. Done.
So even if you have nukes, what's the
what's the moral of the story? Even if
you have nuclear weapons that you
control, if your leadership is stupid,
you may see a situation where your
nuclear weapons are given to your
adversary on a platter. Please, please,
sir, take it.
So, the moral of the story at the end of
the day is that nukes are not sufficient
to save you from a potential invasion by
whoever.
The sufficient condition is nukes plus
the right leadership, competent
leadership that understands the national
interest and will do whatever it takes
to
act on the national interest and put the
national interest first and foremost.
Nukes plus the right leadership.
Your country can have nukes, but if you
have a
not the best leader, not the optimum
leader, your suboptimal leader, God
knows what he or she will do with your
nukes. May give it s please take full
support, sir. Take our nukes. We are a
peaceloving nation. We don't need nukes.
Nukes are bad. Having nuclear weapons is
morally reprehensible.
We will we are Gandhian in nature.
Please take away our nukes. Dismantle
them. Our nuclear program is only for
energy. It's peaceful. That could happen
with the wrong kind of leadership.
Okay.
Okay. Next question is by Ritik Pawar
and Nitishh Kumar Sharma. If Iran falls,
what could what would be the what could
be the consequences for India, Russia
and China? In episode 318, while
discussing Venezuela in the context of
China, you named China's sources of oil.
You mentioned some countries that but
skipped Iran. Did I did I skip Iran?
Okay.
In public documents, Iran doesn't come
up as a major source of oil for China.
But my own digging shows that about that
a lot of Iranian oil is relabeled to
Malaysian, Omani, Emirati tankers
flagged to yeah those those nations
before going to China. In that sense,
Iran supplies about 10 to 15% of oil to
China. U of course China Iran uh 25 year
partnership is also there. With that in
mind, a lot of things start to click. I
think Iran might topple rather soon and
the US is very rapidly making gains to
encircle China. It's all happening in
front of us. Fascinating thoughts. Okay.
I'm not sure what I said in episode 318.
I do remember I listed the sources of
oil in the context of Venezuela. What's
happening there for China? So about 15
20% comes from um from the Saudis, 15
20% comes from Russia. I would say 15%
plus will also come from Iran. And I
must have mentioned at some point in the
episode that the Chinese have this 25
year strategic agreement with Iran in
which one of the one of the clauses and
whatever it is. I mean it's kind of a
secret secret agreement but what's known
is that the Chinese will make massive
investments in the Iranian energy sector
and other other sectors and in exchange
the Chinese will receive copious amounts
of pretty cheap energy from Iran which
is oil.
So yeah 10 15 maybe 20% of of Chinese
oil comes from Iran. Now if the
Americans topple the regime in Thran and
bring about democracy and that democracy
will be controlled by the US. So Iran
will become a US vasal which means the
US will once again control Iranian oil
the way it used to be before 1979.
Before 1979 who controlled Iran's oil?
It was the US.
And now once again once if this happens
a regime change in in in Thran in Iran
then the Americans will once again
control Iranian oil. Maybe they will
allow the Iranian a new government to
export some oil to China. Maybe they
will not. So that then becomes u you
know um the Americans can exercise
whatever choice they want. That's that
becomes the situation
right. Uh so it looks like Iran may fall
soon.
Then the question is
uh what could be the consequences for
India, China, Russia.
Okay, let's first deal with India. Uh we
haven't opened the map yet. So let's
let's go and take a look at what the map
has to tell us. Okay, let's see the map.
And uh here is the map. Let's remove the
question from the screen for a bit. So
we're talking about Iran here, right?
Iran. So north of Iran, you have the
Caspian Sea. You have the Caucasus
region, Azarbaian, Armenia etc. You have
Turkman many stone, you have Afghanistan
to the east and and
Pakistan to the east. Okay. And uh down
south you have the Persian Gulf, the
straight of Hormuz and the Gulf of Oman.
So if the Americans take Iran,
effect of regime change in Iran and Iran
becomes American property essentially,
then
everything will change in the region.
the Americans can they don't anymore
need to blockade the trade of hormones.
Uh the support that that the Yemeni
Ansarah faction or the Houthi faction
gets from the Iranians will stop
entirely which will make it very easy
for the Americans to um I mean not very
easy but easier for the Americans to do
a regime change in uh in Yemen as well.
Um what else will happen? Armenia could
fall. See Armenia is being the Turks and
the Azarbaijanis want to erase Armenia
from the map of the world. The Turks
want to create a pantheran corridor from
Turkey all the way to uh Turk Manistan
across the Caspian Sea by wiping out
Armenia from the map of the world. They
want to the Turks want to conclude what
they what they started in the 1890s all
all the way to 1915, right? They want to
conclude that and Armenia is surviving
because India is supplying weapons to
Armenia through Iran. So the Iranians
are delivering Indian weapons to Armenia
by road. So Armenia could very rapidly
fall. If Iran becomes a US asset, then
if Iran becomes a US asset, then look at
the subcontinent.
Iran is a US asset. Pakistan is a US
asset. Afghanistan is kind of dependent
on the US for for money etc. Yeah.
So what you could have very soon if Iran
falls to the US is you could soon have
American troops in Pakistan occupied
Kashmir.
In in in recent years you had the
situation where you had Chinese troops
in Pakistan occupied Kashmir.
Right. Correct. You had that situation.
You had you had Chinese troops in
Pakistan occupied Kashmir. Now China and
Pakistan are no longer in that
relationship that they had. Okay. Um
the Pakistan is now a US asset, US
Vasal. If Iran also becomes a US vasal,
then that gives Pakistan tremendous
strategic depth. It gives the American
strategic depth in the region. Um the
Balasthan issue goes is over. They will
be able to deal with it. And the
Americans may even have American troops
coming all the way into Pakistan
occupied Kashmir and knocking on India's
door. Okay. And in case there is an
operation 2.0
then Iran will come to the aid of
Pakistan.
So that's these are some of the
implications for India. If Iran falls,
we know that it's the regime of the
moolas. We know it's deeply unpopular in
Iran. We know that the people of Iran
want freedom from this.
We I understand I I completely
understand that and from the perspective
of the Iranian people maybe they need a
need a change. Yeah. But for India from
India's perspective it's going to be a
disaster the moment there's a regime
change in Thran because it's going to be
a pro- US and pro Pakistan regime that
comes into power. They will say nice
things about India. Okay. Indians love
nice words. And the moment there's a
regime change and new regime says nice
things about Indian India Indians will
start dancing. No, everything is good.
No, there's no no problem. Wait and
watch. Ignore the words. See the actions
that will come later.
So if there is operation sindu 2.0, Iran
will support Pakistan
and you will have most likely soon
American troops or maybe Iranian troops,
not Ian troops, maybe American troops in
Pakistan occup.
Uh what about uh China? If Iran falls
well then China loses
you know potentially loses the 15 20% of
um you know energy that it imports from
Iran. So if you look at China's pi 100%
pi 15 20% comes from Saudi Arabia 15 20%
comes from Russia 15 10 15 20% comes
from Iran then you have nations like
Iraq then you have nations like uh
Nigeria and Angola and so on it's got a
basket you know it's a diversified
basket of places from which it acquires
oil and gas
chunk chunk now is controlled by the US
which is Iran Iraq is also controlled by
the US Saudi Arabia UAE All of that is
also controlled by the US. Nigeria is
also controlled by the US. Everything
essentially whatever China imports from,
all the places now become controlled by
the US except for Russia. That forces
China and Russia closer together.
And what's the consequences for Russia?
Well, Russia can no longer acquire the
Shahed drones and whatever drones it was
buying from Iran, it loses an ally south
of the Caspian and it gets more
isolated.
Right.
So yeah, it's it's going to be a domino
effect if Thran falls and it looks like
it could fall any time now.
Real Vladimir Putin says why does
Taliban and Pakistani dictatorship keep
on fighting if both are US vasals?
Abinov Singh says if both Pakistan and
Afghanistan which is Taliban are
effectively US assets, why does
Washington allow them to remain
adversaries? Wouldn't it make more
strategic sense for the US to broker
peace between the two? A united front
would seemingly give the US more control
in the region and a better position to
control India. Right? So why are the
Taliban and the and the Pakistanis at
loggerheads? Why are they enemies? Why
do they hate each other? Why do they
keep fighting? Both are American vasals.
Now, how do we make the claim that the
Taliban are US? They're not quite US was
but they are on the US payroll. Look,
the Americans had a long series of
negotiations with the Taliban before
they handed power to the Taliban in
2021. And then after the long series of
negotiations, there was the Dha Accord
between the US and the Taliban. In the
Dha Accord, there are secret clauses
that have never been revealed to the
world. So it is alleged by very credible
sources that the Americans pay the
Taliban a stipend weekly stipend of
between $50 to $100 million in cash and
that helps the Taliban to run
Afghanistan and you know take care of
business of running the nation and what
do the US get in exchange for the money
they are spending on the Taliban? Well,
the deal most likely would be to keep
the Chinese out of Afghanistan. The
Chinese have this great ambition. This
belt and road initiative, one belt to
rule you, one belt to ru rule you all
and that sort of thing, right?
One ring to rule them all,
something to bind them, that sort of
thing. Um, [laughter]
so the the Chinese want to use Afghan
territory to push westwards and create
infrastructure to Afghan territory,
road, roads, rail, whatever. And the
Chinese want to invest in the
Afghanistan copper sector, the oil and
gas, gas gas sector, maybe other
minerals and so on. And the Afghans have
never allowed this to happen. Ever since
they came to power, ever since the
Taliban came to power, it's not
happened. Nothing has happened. So maybe
that's the deal. You keep the Chinese
out. You don't allow China any access to
Afghan territory and Afghan resources.
And maybe you keep the Russians also at
arms length. In exchange for that, we
will give you whatever amount of dollars
we're giving in cash every week. You
hold your end of the bargain, we hold
our end of the bargain. That's the deal
between the US and the Afghans. And the
Taliban.
So the Taliban from that perspective you
could say is kind of a US asset. The
Pakistanis we know are American vasals,
bootlickers, shoe shiners, right? That
that's what aim is.
So why can't the Americans
ensure that Pakistan and Afghanistan
don't fight? Well, that's not in
America's control. Let's understand the
two perspectives. This here is Pakistan.
This here is Afghanistan. Pakistan. All
the Pakistani generals, RB people, etc.
Their bank accounts, they have secret
bank accounts in the west
probably in London or whatever. And all
their relatives live in the west. Some
live in the US, some live in the UK,
etc. So, they are all actually invested
in the west. Their entire family's
future is in the west. Their all their
money is in the west. And whatever
they're doing in Pakistan is to extract
more money and send it to the bank
accounts. That's what the Pakistanis are
doing. The Pakistanis. Now, name one
Taliban commander who has any assets
outside of of the of Afghanistan. Name
one Taliban commander who has family in
in the west. I assure you the num the
number is zero.
Okay.
So there is no leverage the Americans
have over the Agans in that manner that
they can force the Taliban to behave in
this way or that way. The Taliban are
pashon nationalists. They hate the
Pakistanis
and they want their territory back.
So the Americans are in no position to
dictate to the Taliban to become to to
to hug and make up with the Pakistanis.
That will never happen. Okay, that's the
situation. There can never be unity
between the Pakistanis and the Afghans,
especially as as long as Taliban the
Taliban is ruling. Even when you had a
non- Taliban government ruling
Afghanistan, the the relationship was
pretty chilly, pretty cold between
Pakistan and Afghanistan.
Um the Afghans, the Pashons regard the
Pakistanis as their blood enemies with
ancient with an ancient feud that goes
back to the 19th century, right? And the
Pakistanis occupy Afghan territory,
Pashon territory. you're never going to
have peace between the two until um you
know the territorial dispute is resolved
and it has to be resolved in such a way
that the puns regain their territory
which means the map of Pakistan has to
change and karakuna has to become part
of Afghanistan that is the only
long-term solution to the issue but the
Pakistan is not will not allow that
right big territory big resources why
will they allow that so that's the issue
so the Americans can't do a thing about
that they can't force the Taliban to
make up with the Pakistanis will never
happen.
Rushup tar says could you please explain
about the Russia sanctions bill? Howard
Lutnik's admission not admission claim
Howard Lutnik Lutnik's claim that the
trade deal between the US and India is
not happening because Prime Minister
Modi has not called Mr. Trump. Trump is
releasing hats of make of making India
of making Iran great again is
threatening Kame Kame. Uh moreover he
has demanded Greenland which could very
well make NATO obsolete. My question is
what exactly is Donald J. Trump trying
to achieve by creating chaos across the
world and destroying the world order
they themselves created. Look Donald J.
Trump is just doing what he is supposed
to do.
See the president of the US is not the
final decision maker of what happens in
the US. Okay? He's not the ultimate
power in the United States. The power
lies somewhere else. President just does
what what he supposed to do. And there
have been presidents in the past who
have refused to do what the real power
wants. And then you have situations like
1963.
So DJT look Donald. Trump wants to be
remembered as the greatest, biggest,
baddest, greatest president in American
history since Abraham Lincoln or since
George Washington or maybe the greatest
ever. I'm the best president ever,
right? That sort of thing. So, he's
happy to have the full might of the US
establishment be behind him. When he was
president from 2016 to 2020, he was
essentially just a lame duck president.
The establishment was against him. But
this time he has kissed the ring and the
entire might of the establishment is
behind him and he's carrying out their
agenda. Right?
Uh is he creating chaos across the world
and destroying the world order? The
question you to ask yourselves my dear
friends is this world order that the
Americans created post 1945
it served US interests. It allowed the
US to expand its military footprint
across the world to expand its power
projection capabilities across the world
and they created this this you know
rules-based world allegedly rules-based
world order etc. But by the late n 20th
century early 21st century who did this
world order serve more it served the
Chinese. The Chinese learned they
understood how to how to use the system
for their own benefit. Right. It served
the Chinese. It and now you have this
the spectre of multi-polarity coming up.
The Americans don't want multipolarity.
They talk about G2. They want a G1. They
want to be the sole hedgeimon across the
world all all around the world.
They're not creating chaos. They're
reorganizing the system in a way that
suits them better. Now,
okay. So, they want to be the one
stable, powerful, rich, magnificently
rich, lavishly rich country in the
world. and all other nations have to be
supplicants, minions, vasals. That's
what the Americans want. And to make
this happen, you have to do surgery on
the world order, right? Surgery. Surgery
you to do on the world order. That's
what the US is doing right now.
Um, yeah. So, okay. Now, coming back to
the sanctions bill, Russia sanctions
bill. So, this is a bill that's been
proposed by what, Lindsey Graham and
whoever else. Yeah. Not sure who the
names are. Um,
and the bill says it's not been passed
in in in the US legislative process thus
far. Donald Trump has green lit the bill
which means that it will go to Congress
or whatever it will have to go um and
and uh go in front of the Congress and
they to vote on it and if it passes then
first of all the bill will apply 500%
tariffs on Russia
in case Russia is not co cooperating in
ending the Ukraine war or whatever which
is like it's a given right so it's going
to apply 500% tariffs on Russia it's
going to impose all kinds of sanctions
further sanctions on Russia and so on so
the objective was to devastate Russia
and constrain Russia economically.
Then the bill also has secondary
sanctions applied at N which will be
applied on nations that purchase Russian
oil because that obviously uh finances
the Russian war machine, Russia's war on
Ukraine. So nations like China, India,
Brazil, etc. who purchase Russian oil,
they're going to be hit with 500%
tariffs. So for India it will devastate
India's trade relationship with the US
because we don't have a trade deal thus
far. If you have a trade deal then that
is exempt right but the trade deal isn't
hasn't happened. So it be it will be
very bad for India India US relations.
It will put India in a position where we
have to choose this or that.
We either choose to continue purchasing
oil from Russia and then our trade
relationship with the US goes for a toss
completely utterly or we stop buying
Russian oil which is we have fallen prey
to the arm twisting then the Americans
will progressively impose more demands
on India. So this is the road to
vasalage the road to wasalhood status.
That's what the Americans want for
India. They want India to become an
American vasal. Well if if you were the
US you would want that obviously. Come
on.
about the trade deal. See, Lutnik has
claimed that we had the trade deal all
set up. All that was needed now was for
by Mr. Modi to pick up the phone and
call Donald Trump and Mr. Modi was not
comfortable doing that and that's why
the trade deal hasn't happened. So,
Lutnik is putting all the blame on
India.
Do we know that he is speaking the
truth?
There is no guarantee. There's no
assurance that he is speaking the truth.
This could just be another pressure
tactic. Lie on camera.
The Trump regime is is known for for
making all kinds of, you know,
fantastical claims. I have stopped seven
wars. I stopped Star Wars.
Yeah. Star Wars was happening in a
different galaxy. I stopped it. He's
claiming that he stopped all kinds of
wars and he's the most peaceful
president. Peaceful. Okay. So, look,
whatever they say, it doesn't mean it's
really what what happened.
I imagine there was no trade deal that
was that was finalized.
And if there was a trade deal that was
good good for both countries, Prime
Minister Modi would have done whatever
it took,
including calling Mr. Trump or whatever
to get the deal finalized and signed.
The Americans are adopting a maximalist
position in their negotiations with
India. They are saying, "Open your
market completely.
Open your market totally the agriculture
sector, the dairy sector. Let us dump
our GMO genetically modified products
into India. So India will soon have all
the all the health problems the
Americans have. Right? Open your market
0% tariffs on American goods. So what
happens if we do that? There are people
in India who are complaining that the
American tariffs 50% that is there right
now it's it's really hurting Indian
industries and businesses. Okay,
for sure it'll be hurting Indian
businesses.
Imagine if we
if we bend the knee. If imagine if India
caves in and says, "Okay, America, we
are opening our market to you. Zero
tariffs. Do what? Dump whatever you want
into to to dump into India." Then India
becomes a big market, captive market for
the US. Hen the Americans dump all their
goods into India, which will put all
Indian businesses out of business. Then
who's going to take care of those
businesses? If Indian businesses are
being hurt right now, imagine what
happens if we open up the market.
All Indian businesses and industries
will close down, shut down because the
Americans, they will dump their goods at
the cheapest rates. Their goods, no
question, you know, apart from dairy,
all that, apart from agriculture and
dairy, the goods are high quality and
they'll price them such that they will
price, they'll outco compete all the
Indian manufacturers.
India wants to become a manufacturing
nation, right? This is going to be the
death blow to that. So the Americans
want to essentially vaselize India in
multiple ways. Vasalize India by by
destroying India's manufacturing sector
by turning India into a captive market.
Vasilize India through other means by by
controlling all the all the oil that
flows into India and forcing India to
show to stop buying Russian oil.
Versalize India through other means. all
kinds of means are there uh by by
supporting Pakistan perhaps if Iran
fourth then Pakistan Iran combined will
be against India so that's the situation
India is going to face a lot of pressure
going forward
okay three questions and there's plenty
more but I've taken three as
illustrative questions
um for this for this particular question
okay
Vladimir Putin says Saudi Arabia is a US
vasal in that case why does it export
petroleum to China and also have the
have the dealings in in Chinese yuan
interesting question ultimate power a1
says what's the issue that's going on
between Saudi Arabia and UAE I saw you
speaking about it in a recent podcast
can you please explain it and brianka
biswas says with Saudi Arabia's
potential purchase of Chinese jets
through Pakistan is Riyad trying to
drift away from US influence especially
as as backs rivals to uh US aligned UAE
forces in in South Yemen. Also, if not,
why is China allowing this as technology
can fall under US supervision? See,
okay, first let's talk about the jets.
The the Pakistanis owe a lot of money to
to the Saudis, right? The Pakistanis owe
a lot of money. They always go to the
Saudis with a begging ball. The Saudis
always bail the Pakistanis out by giving
them some loans. Do the Pakistanis have
to repay the loans at some point in
time. The Pakistanis are saying, "We
don't have money. We have some fighter
planes that we purchased from from the
Chinese or maybe we are jointly
developing some fighter planes the JF7
or whatever with the Chinese. We will
sell we will give you some of these
fighter jets in lie of the money that we
owe you. And the Saudis are interested.
They are willing to buy. Now these
fighter planes JF7s that the Pakistanis
are building
jointly with the Chinese. These are
export versions. That's not the full
version. The full the Chinese don't even
use the JF7. It's it's a MIG 21
derivative with some advanced more
advanced uh features. That's what it is.
And it's it's simply an export version
variant of of export fighter jet. The
Chinese themselves don't use it as far
as I understand. They have other fighter
planes. They use more advanced fifth
generation etc planes and they have the
Sukhoy knockoffs and all the Chinese and
so on. Yeah. So um this technology is
not that that sensitive. If it falls
into American American hands, the
Chinese the Chinese are okay with it.
It's not it's not like some big uh
technological secrets are going to fall
into American hands. Okay. So the Saudis
are very strongly considering acquiring
these Pakistani Chinese fighter jets
from the Pakistanis.
Uh the Saudis have been selling oil to
China and they have been taking the
money from the Chinese in Yuan which is
very naughty very naughty naughty. Uh
and then there's the issue between Saudi
Arabia and the UAE. H
so there's
lot of complicated stuff going on here.
What is the complication? How do we
unravel the complication is the
question.
See the Saudis Saudi Arabia is a much
larger country than the UE much larger
country. And the Saudis want to survive
the 21st century. They know that oil is
not not going to be the end of you know
won't be around forever.
You know in the stone age everybody
needed stones and stones were valuable
but today stones have no value.
Similarly in the oil age everybody
needed oil and that's why Saudi Arabia
became so prosperous but eventually the
world may move on from oil and into
other sources of energy. Then what
happens? So the Saudis are trying to
plan for that and the Saudis they are
you could say aligned with the US very
strongly. They recently purchased a
tremendous amount of American arms
ammunition weapons that pleased Mr.
Trump. But the Saudis also have their
own interests
and the UAE
is very closely aligned with the US and
Israel also.
Okay. And uh the Saudis in the UAE are
on opposite sides kind of in Yemen. The
Saudis and the UE are also allegedly on
opposite opposite sides in whatever is
happening in Sudan. They are backing
opposing factions. Rapid support Fox
forces and the other one that sort of
thing. So there is a rivalry between
Saudi Arabia and the UAE. Okay, there is
a rivalry and the UAE is more closely
aligned with Israel and the United
States and Saudi Arabia wants to
diversify, wants to perhaps hedge its
bets bets and have have diverse friends,
right? U so that is the situation.
Um
and the UA seems to be kind of you know
brotherly nations and all but but that
is the deal. So Saudi Arabia is because
Saudi Arabia has been dealing with China
selling a large amount of oil to the
Chinese and and dealing in yuan real
yuan kind of thing. uh that obviously is
not going to please the Americans or the
Israelis
and uh
and the UAE is also a you know pretty
robust actor in the region. They also
have a reasonably strong military and so
on. So that is the rivalry that's
happening right now. Uh how it will turn
out, how it will go, we'll have to wait
and watch.
Right. Next.
Okay. Ritik Pawar says, "Why does Trump
want Greenland? First, if he makes a
move on Greenland, will it would it
trigger NATO's article 5? Secondly, how
would the EU respond?" Karthik says,
"What's Trump's real intent behind his
threats to take over Greenland?" He
keeps mentioning it's for national
security. Yes, it does, right? To cover
against Chinese and Russian
expansionism. But the US also already
has an army base in Greenland. Why
aren't they trying to go their
conventional route of not of of having
more bases in the country and vasilizing
the country?
Right. Right. Right. So, what does Trump
want?
Why does he want Greenland? So, to see,
let's go to the map and let's understand
where Greenland is located and what's
the uh strategic importance of
Greenland. Let's put the map on the
screen and and navigate to that part of
the world.
So we are talking about we go west west
west west west west west west west west
west west west west west from India west
west west and then we are in the arctic
ocean and this here is greenland it
looks gigantic from here it's not that
big it's because of the projection the
way things are projected okay and
greenland belongs to Denmark Denmark
this little country over here yeah
Denmark
um
whose capital is Kubern heaven. So
Denmark somehow owns green uh Greenland.
Okay. The how how does it how did it end
up owning Greenland? That's a whole
different story. We'll not go there. Now
if you look at it from this perspective,
Greenland sits between the northern
Russian region and North America. And if
the Russians were to potentially let's
say launch ballistic missiles
um at the US uh if you have early
warning uh stations etc in Greenland
then you can very quickly uh detect such
launches and send a warning back to the
United States and Greenland obviously
it's a large
large region and it has substantial
deposits of oil and gas. It also has
substantial deposits of other resources,
other minerals and so on. So, it's
pretty valuable. The United States wants
to acquire
completely sovereign, it wants sovereign
capture over large territories that are
rich in resources.
In the case of Venezuela, that's a whole
population that lives there. So you
can't
you can't acquire it
in the fact in in the sense of having
sovereign control over Venezuela. So you
vasalize Venezuela. When it comes to
Iran, you can vasalize Iran because you
have a big population that you can't put
boots on the ground. But Greenland is
mainly empty. How what's the population
of Greenland? Let's quickly take a look
at that. Maybe a couple thousand people,
maybe 10,000. I don't know. Let's see.
What's the population of Greenland?
Population
of Greenmen.
What's the population? 56 to 57,000
people. Give each of them a million
dollars. Done deal. They will all vote
to uh become US citizens.
And uh so because it's got such a small
population, it's a huge territory, it
makes sense for the US to just take it
over, you know, just gobble it up. And
what can Denmark do? Nothing.
What what what are they going to do?
defend some soldiers. Come on, that's
not going to work. The Americans already
have this thu base or whatever it is,
but they want to acquire the entire
territory and use it for a variety of
purposes. They want they may put up more
military bases. They set up mining
operations and so on. Uh the Americans
want to take formal sovereign control of
as many resources as possible. There's
also the Russian angle like I said the
Chinese angle also the Chinese may may
have interests in the region. the
Russians and Chinese as we know are
cooperating. So that's the that's the
thing. So uh Trump wants Greenland and
it's most likely going to happen sooner
or later. So that's why Greenland is is
something that Trump desires. It makes
sense from a material perspective from a
security strategic perspective from the
perspective of the location geographical
location of the place from the
perspective of it having oil and gas
minerals and other resources. Yeah.
So now the question is
if the Americans take Greenland, will it
trigger NATO's article 5? See Denmark
which owns Greenland is a member of
NATO. The US is the owner of NATO and
the and a member member of NATO and you
have a bunch of other countries that are
members of NATO. The deal is NATO's
article 5 says that if any of the NA
member states of NATO comes under
attack, it's to be treated as an attack
on everybody else and everybody is
supposed to come to the defense of the
nation that's a member of NATO that's
been attacked. But that article 5, it
talks about external attack from a
non-NATO member. But what if a NATO
member attacks a NATO member? What
happens then? and that NATO member is
the US, the overlord, the supreme
hedgeim, the owner of NATO. What
happens? There's nothing NATO nations
can do about this. This will most likely
lead to NATO ceasing to exist as a as a
functioning block, as a functioning
alliance.
It may fragment NATO. It may destroy
NATO entirely.
NATO may no longer operate after this.
other nations may perhaps potentially
withdraw from NATO and the US maybe
that's what the US wants. Maybe the US
wants to deal with every nation onetoone
instead of dealing with a bunch of
nations together. It actually makes
sense if you're really powerful to not
have these big loose alliances or
whatever. Deal with each nation one to
one. Vasilize each nation one to one.
Put your armed forces on each nation one
to one on one.
That way you have better, more rigorous,
more granular control than going through
the NATO bureaucracy and all that. Maybe
it makes sense. So maybe the Americans
have decided it's time to end NATO and u
maybe Greenland a move on Greenland
could be the trigger that that ends
NATO. Uh how will the EU respond? So the
EU is not NATO. It's a different thing,
right? The EU is is this bureaucratic
block based out of Brussels. What will
the EU do? How could or would the EU
respond? Well, the EU will issue
protests. [snorts] The EU will uh issue
strange uh strong statements. The EU may
do some strong diplomacy. The EU may
decide to impose sanctions on the US.
[laughter]
That sort of thing. Yeah. I don't think
the EU will dare impose sanctions on on
the US because the bureaucrats who run
the EU, they can be very badly, brutally
sanctioned by the Americans and that
will make their life lives miserable. So
I don't think there's much the EU can do
about this.
So maybe the US has decided it's time to
end NATO. We will deal with all of these
European nations onetoone, one-on-one.
We will manage them individually instead
of managing them as a coalition.
that gives the US way more control over
each individual nation.
So you can recreate the EU the the NATO
like circumstances individually with
with with each each nation and make it
even more rigorous, right? So maybe
that's what the US wants. So looks like
Greenland could happen soon. Greenland
is there's no urgency there. The
Americans can wait maybe until Iran is
done or something. So you're going to
see a lot of changes maybe in this year
2026.
Aush Singh says other powers fight from
their homeland but the US fights
in their homeland far away from its own
land its own territory. Don't you think
it alone is a very large advantage they
have the Americans they don't have to
worry about their nation they can cause
as much destruction as possible in other
nations. What my take what's my take on
this? So it's the advantage the US has.
You know the US is the sole hedgemen in
the Americas. Let's go back to the map.
Give me a second. Let's put the map back
on the screen. Okay. The US is the sole
hedgeimon in the Americas. Okay. We'll
go to the Americas. The Western
Hemisphere, the US is the only nation
that matters. All other nations in North
and South America, they cowtow the US.
The US controls the the fate of every
nation and and essentially dictates the
policies each each nation should have.
Um right and the great advantage the US
has is all the nations over here in the
region none of them can pose any kind of
military threat to the US. It's
impossible that Canada or Mexico or
Venezuela or Colombia or Nicaragua or
Brazil or whoever Arantina.
None of the these nations has anything
like the hard power the US has. The US
faces no threat whatsoever. They have
engineered the situation wonderfully.
And when it comes to national security
from other nations, non-hemispheric
nations, well, the US is protected
in the east by the Atlantic Ocean. in
the west by the gigantic Pacific Ocean,
right? Um, so the US is super secure and
the US has more than 800 extr
territorial military bases spread across
the world. The US owns Australia. The US
owns the five eyes nations. The US owns
Japan, South Korea. The US controls, you
know, all the nations in the region,
Southeast Asia. They're aligned with US
objectives. They don't dare cross the
line with the US. The US essentially
owns Africa, EU, NATO, all of that. So
you see the US,
it has built up built up these
capabilities over the past century or
so. And it is essentially kind of
invincible. It has the most destructive
power of any empire ever in in human
history.
And see this did not happen overnight.
They worked really hard for this. So
whatever they have today, they have
worked for it. They have built it up and
they deserve it. And since they have it,
they're going to use it. They won't
allow any any other nation to to rise up
and become a competitor and adversary.
They have made that mistake with China,
but they're going to they're putting all
the pieces in place to cut China down to
size and they'll deal with Russia as
well. And they want India to be
vitalized. So the Americans can unleash
war on any country they want and they
don't have to worry about war coming
about war visiting them in their
homeland. That's a great advantage a
nation can have and they have it. Yeah.
Swami says do you think India as of
today is on the cusp of change? I did
the math. If India grows at 10% for 30
years or 7% for 45 50 years or 4% for
100 years, India will surpass everyone
and become the largest economy in the
world. Also, what should India do to
ensure this? Everyone is against us. How
will we win if the superpower is against
us? But the superpower will naturally be
against you. See, mathematically, you
are absolutely right.
See, India has all the potential. India
has the territory. India has the
population. India has the resources.
India has a wonderful geographical
location. Forget about the kind of
wonderful labors we have but
geographically we dominate the Indian
Ocean region right India has all the
potential to be a dominant power perhaps
to be the dominant power in the world in
the next 50 years maybe it'll start
showing signs and symptoms of this in
the next 20 years in 50 years it will
probably be the largest economy or the
second largest very close to the largest
economy [gasps]
but that is assuming
India's economy keeps growing at
whatever percentage let's say it's 7 8%
even if it's 6%
50 years should be enough yeah for India
to be close to the largest economy in
the world so mathematically it just
makes sense just keep doing okay work 6%
growth per year it's enough but the
other nations won't allow this to happen
they don't want this to happen the US
doesn't want that to happen the Chinese
also don't want want this to happen
so the question is what should India do
to ensure this? Everyone is against us.
Number one, India has to ensure it
anyhow remains a sovereign nation. Don't
allow someone to vasalize you.
Very very very hard thing to ensure.
But if India loses its its sovereignty
then no matter what economic growth you
get, the beneficiary is going to be the
overlord sitting outside.
So India has to anyhow retain its
sovereignty. Secondly, India has to
ensure it doesn't get embroiled in some
kind of military
situation,
right? Any any kind of military conflict
because military conflicts will drain
your GDP growth. They'll drain your
economy potentially and cause damage
potentially. So at least 20 years India
should not get involved in any major
military conflict. Taught sharp war
somewhere it's fine but nothing major
nothing. to nothing that could be a
damaging factor to the Indian economic
growth.
And at the end of the day, if you have a
100 million Bangladeshes in India, then
what's the point of your mil of your
economic growth? They're going to
multiply faster than you.
And all this economic growth you're
making, you're building up, you're going
to hand it to their descendants.
So what the hell is the government of
India doing?
So that has to be to be dealt with.
potentially 100 million Bangladeshes in
India, illegal Bangladeshi infiltrators
and god knows how many other what what
kind of people. Yeah, that's an issue.
And then if you have economic growth,
you're growing but the quality of your
population is low, then what do you do?
What's the point?
If your population is mentally
colonized,
then what's the point of economic
growth?
So you have to reform the system.
You have to reform the education system.
You have to reform clean up the
bureaucracy and whatn not. Whatever
issues exist, those have to be
addressed. So all that needs to be done.
We can't say that okay, we will start
doing this when when we are 10 trillion
economies. Why don't why not start right
now?
The Chinese put all the pieces in place
when they were smaller than India's
economy.
They started reforming the education
system long long ago in the in the 1980s
and '90s when they were not even $4
trillion economy.
India is pushing all those reforms and
all those all that hard things all those
all all those hard things to the to the
future. Maybe the future generations
will do it. The future generations will
be completely mentally colonized.
So these things need to be addressed.
But the most important thing is do not
matter what happens don't lose your
sovereignty. That's what India needs to
do and that lies in the hands of the
government.
Real Vadir Putin says couple of
questions related to the Myanmar civil
war. First of all, what's the issue with
Myanmar? Second, who are the big players
in the Myanmar civil war? Third, how
does it benefit them? Fourth, what's the
role of India in this? Okay, let us go
to map.
Here is map. Where is Myanmar? We go
back to the subcontinent. Okay, this is
India. And to the east of India, we have
this large nation called Myanmar, right?
And we have this trijunction here.
India, Myanmar, China.
And if we go down south, we have a
trijunction here. India, Myanmar,
Bangladesh. Where is Pakistan? And then
Myanmar has a border with Thailand,
right? And that's about it. And also a
border with Laos.
So that's Myanmar. It's supposed to be
it's look historically it's it's been
part of Indian civilization. Uh the
people of Myanmar culturally are pretty
much Indian. Uh they are probably
more Indian than most Indians including
Yeah. So that's that's Myanmar. Now
what's the deal? What's the issue with
Myanmar? See uh since the 1940s Myanmar
whenever Myanmar got its independence
which year was it when did Myanmar
become independent? When did Myanmar
get independence? Uh 48 1948 is when
Myanmar became independent. Since then
Myanmar has been ruled by the military
of Myanmar. Okay. The military wanted a
strong nation to be its supporter. They
would have liked India to be that
nation. But India was never interested
in in being strong itself. So the
Myanmar's
army militia ha it aligned with China.
Now so Myanmar was aligned with China
for the longest time. It kind of still
is to some extent. Okay. Myanmar is rich
in resources, natural resources, oil,
gas, a lot of gas and rare earths. If
you go to the north of Myanmar, okay,
not far from India, you will see all
kinds of rare earth, you know, mines
being being operationalized.
Where do we have it? Okay, I need to put
that part of the map back in.
Um, where is it? Is it here?
Okay, I'll let's see. Let's quickly zoom
in here. Do we see? Yeah, here we have
something. These are rare earth mines.
No, probably not this but somewhere
nearby
you will have okay mine pit rare earth
mining is happening here. So very close
to the Chinese border we have a rare
earth mines okay that the myanmaries are
working on and all of that is exported
to to the Chinese. Let me see here
quickly.
Do we have something happening here?
Yeah you have some mining activity
happening here. So if you know what to
look for and if you have the time to
look into it, you will you will find
significant
uh rare earth mining activity happening
here. So if Myanmar is a nation that has
rare earths and it knows how to process
them, that makes Myanmar a very
important nation. The Chinese are
benefiting from the rare earths that the
Myanmaries are processing. The Americans
want that. the northern part of Myanmar.
Okay, let's go back to the map. So, the
northern parts of Myanmar, okay, these
used to be Hindu,
these were Hindu regions. For example,
the kingdom of Manipur had an alliance
with the kingdom of Pong in the north of
Myanmar.
And the king of Pong after a joint
military campaign with the king of
Manipur which was successful, the king
of Pong gifted a Vishnu idol to the king
of Manipur. So, the northern part of
Myanmar was Hindu. Today the northern
part of Myanmar is entirely converted to
Christianity. So the British who after
the 1940s spend a lot of time the
British actually the Americans who spend
a lot of time in the far east of India
converting Nagaland Manipur Mizoram all
these people to Christianity. Manipur
still survives but Nagaland is almost
completely converted. They are doing
that in Arunachal also now. So while
they were converting India's
northeastern people, far eastern people
to Christianity, they were doing the
same thing in Myanmar as well. So in the
northern parts of Myanmar, you have
Christianity all over the place. And
those people are no longer aligned with
the government of Myanmar. They don't
they they don't they don't see
themselves as Burmese anymore. They are
culturally western Christian. In the
same situation the Americans have done
across Southeast Asia, Laos, uh Vietnam,
the in the mountainous regions of
Vietnam, they converted everybody. So
wherever you have these conversions, you
have militancy, you have insurgency, you
have antinational movements, you have
breakaway separatist, separatist
movements and so on. Uh so that's the
situation. So today Myanmar is in civil
war. Okay. The Myanmar is aligned with
the west for a while. They had
Sanansuchi who was their leader and who
became the the the
prime minister, president of Myanmar,
whatever, right? But then she became a
Myanmar's patriot and she tried to crack
down on the Rohhinga terrorists which is
why the Americans uh stopped liking her
and then there was a coup recently in
Myanmar and the army took over again. So
today the army of Myanmar is kind of in
control of half the nation. The half the
nation is aligned with China or whoever
is going to willing to pay them the best
money and we have the entire cookie land
for Christ issue that comes out of this
this this matter. uh the the west wants
to create an artificial Christian
Pakistan out of parts of northern
Myanmar, Manipur, Misoram etc. right to
cut India's access to Eastern Asia. We
our access to northern Asia is cut off.
Our access to western Asia is cut off by
Pakistan and China. Now they want to cut
off our access to Eastern Asia. In the
past 70 80 years, India has not built a
single road, single highway that
connects the far east of India, Manipur,
etc. to Laos, Cambodia, Vietnam,
wherever we have not bothered to do a
thing. Our governments have been
sleeping. So since we have been sleeping
even in the past 11 years, now we have a
situation and now Manipur is under
cookie occupation. Half of Manipur and
that's that's a situation. So India's
role in this is and and these folks they
not only do this rare earth mining and
all they do opium mining. Opium is then
refined into heroin or whatever drug it
is. Cocaine not cocaine probably
heroine,
right? Um and and that's how they you
know they acquire money to to purchase
arms, ammunition and all that. Uh and
that's also happening in India's
Manipur, right? So the big players in
Myanmar civil war, who are they? It's
the US and China. It's a proxy war. The
northern part is controlled by the
Chinese. The Americans also have the
cookies on their side. And the
government of Myanmar, the military
wants to somehow remain independent
somehow. Maybe we'll see about that.
And that's the deal. So it's a
geopolitical issue. The civil war is is
being instigated from outside.
And what's the India's what's India's
role in this? I don't know what role
India is playing in this. We have
allowed I don't know how many lacks of
Myanmar's origin cookies to squat in
Manipur and take over our territory and
and and uh besiege the people of Manipur
in the small impal region.
uh Manipur is the last bastion of
Hinduism in India's far east apart from
a little bit in Tripura.
Um I'm not sure what India's role in
this is. India's role is always
reactive. Nothing proactive ever right.
There was some talk of India gaining
some Myanmar's territory if the cookies
become on India's side. Some some sort
of nonsensical dream like that.
See these folks they don't identify with
India. They have no allegiance to India
as a nation. They have no allegiance to
India as a civilization. Um they not
even they don't even have allegiance to
Burma. You can't trust them. Um and they
are allied with the west.
And there are some other nations also
involved in this that I will not name
here. Okay. There are certain other full
support nations involved in this.
Sharma says, "Could you explain how and
why the northeast of India is now
majority Christian and how it all ties
to Manipur and Bangladesh? It seems
really complex. How does the US have a
role to play in this and what's the
ultimate objective?" Okay.
See the Chinese and the Japanese
they encountered a taste of Christianity
in the in the previous centuries during
the opium wars that were forced upon
China by the west in the 1800s which the
Chinese called the century of
humiliation. At that time the Chinese
were forced to allow Christian
missionaries in China who then converted
Chinese. And the Chinese wrote that the
Chinese who get converted to
Christianity for a bag of rice, they
called them rice Christians and they
said that they develop extr territorial
loyalties. They become loyal to the west
not to China. The Japanese also wrote
the same thing. The Japanese also also
faced the Christian people the problem.
So the west see the west treats
Christianity as a political religion.
What they do is they will go into your
region if you allow them. They will
convert people who are generally people
who live in isolated regions like tribal
people. They'll convert convert them to
Christianity. These people have no
leadership of their own. So they will
give them external leadership. The
external leadership will report to the
headquarters in in some big capital city
of the world or somewhere. So then these
people they become assets of the west.
Okay. And it's kind of well known that
in in various parts of the far east of
India, Nagaland etc etc it's the church
that runs the show
not the government they collect taxes
they they they decide what happens they
decide what policies will be implemented
who can buy land who cannot buy land in
Manipur we have this apartheid act you
know def factor apathide act where
Hindus can't buy territory outside of
the infal region but others can
um that sort of thing. So it's it's
um now why is the majority Christian?
Because Mr. Nehu the great magnificent
Mr. Nehu in his great wisdom he decided
that no Hindu uh religious people could
go to India's far east to India's
northeast. Okay. But he allowed American
Baptist missionaries to go all over the
place. So around 1900 I would say almost
0% of Nagaland was Christian. By 1980
almost 95 99% of Nagaran must have been
Christian by by 1980. So that's what
happened. Now they are trying to push
that into Arunachal Pradesh. Now even
the Hindu Manipuris the Mateis are now
getting converted to Christianity. Maybe
one or two lakh of them also have
converted. So it's the objective is to
turn the whole of India's far east into
a Christian territory which will then no
longer have allegiance to India
and then you can create trouble and
create separatism and what not.
>> [clears throat]
>> The objective is to make India lose the
far east, the northeast. That's the
objective and we have the chicken's neck
which connects. So that also is a is a
big impediment for India. East Pakistan
has now reemerged out of Bangladesh and
you know there could be trouble coming
out of there. is pretty complex but the
overall objective is very simple
to
re-engineer the religious demographics
of the far east on an industrial scale
to make the far east completely
non-Indian culturally and
civilizationally and then to have the
separatist movements that say that we
are minorities being victimized by the
evil Hindu hindutwa government of India
and we want freedom
you will see all these groups on
Facebook etc cookie groups and whatnot
who are not really even Indian who claim
that we are being oppressed and we are a
nation under Indian occupation and what
not. Yeah. All that is going on
and you have certain Indian activists
who are also involved in these matters.
Big surprise. Yeah. Big surprise. So
that's the objective. The objective is
to break the northeast or far east of
India away from India. That's the
objective. The objective is to cut India
down to size slice by slice.
salami slicing or maybe the whole slice
goes away that sort of thing. The
objective is to destabilize India. The
objective is to eventually fragment
India, turn India into a collection of
the I don't know 30 40 states or
whatever that sort of thing and then
colonize each one of them individually.
Right? The objective is to recreate the
princely state system of India or each
of them is a vasal of the west. That's
the objective.
Ultimate [snorts] power says
is downfall of Europe because of illegal
immigration. Is this downfall beneficial
for India's selfish interest or not?
Currently when I see such videos from
Europe, I stay neutral and I don't
react. Sometimes I feel it's better for
India that Europe is declining as it
will give us more opportunities to move
forward. However, at the same time, if
illegal immigrants offer certain
ideology take over the European
countries one by one, European countries
will become more anti-India. What should
we as people whose interests are in
India do? Should we support
anti-immigration in Europe or support
immigration in Europe? I know both of
the options have their own merits and
demmerits. But which is relatively more
beneficial to us? So you did indeed say
in here that you know if let's say
London London becomes Londonistan and
the UK becomes let's say an Islamic
republic by 2050 is it going to be good
for India or bad for India? See we not
the European nations have historically
opposed and oppressed India.
Various European nations tried to
extract whatever they can could out of
India. The Portuguese, the French, the
the Dutch, the Danes and obviously the
English, the British. Their objectives
were not
good. They were evil evil objectives to
destroy plunder
India and to totally beggar India.
That's the that was their objective. So
when you see this happening to the
European nations a [clears throat] and
even after 1947 after India became a
republic India became independent even
in the 21st century all these nations
are aligned against us.
If you look at the activities of Germany
visav India those are very very
anti-India activities. um the the
reporting that they have about India in
their in their media, their diplomatic
activities, all of these are aligned
against India. Of course, some of them
will have trade deals and agreements
because they seek to benefit from them
from that. But overall, the European
nations are still mostly most of them
are still anti-India.
So now if the European nations become
let's say Islamic republics like you're
saying, will that benefit India?
It may actually be even worse for India
possibly. Yeah. Because in because of
the way India is being portrayed
and uh
for example when you have people like
Sadi Khan who's the mayor of of of
London is he pro India is he neutral? No
he's he's strongly anti-India. When you
have someone like the Mamani fellow
who's now the mayor of New York he is
anti-India. He's not neutral. He's not
pro- India. He's anti-India. Even though
he's of Indian origin. Even Sadik Khan
is of Indian origin. Pakistani which is
the same thing. Same blood. Same blood.
You see DNA doesn't matter. Blood
doesn't matter. So if these European
nations all fall one by one like you say
through immigration they get
demographically re-engineered and they
become let's say Islamic republics or
whatever. Will it be good for India, bad
for India? Overall it'll be perhaps
perhaps worse for India perhaps maybe 5%
10% worse for India potentially
but the question is look Europe is
facing this problem of illegal
immigration right and the Europeans are
are pained by it but they can't do a
thing because it's the EU governments
the EU regime that is imposing
immigration on the European nations they
can't do a thing about it but what about
India
do we fail to recognize that we are
facing tremendous mendous illegal
immigration way more than Europe. In
2014,
it was said in parliament by the
government of India that there may be
about 5 crore Bangladeshes, illegal
Bangladeshes in India. That there are
about 5 crore illegal Bangladeshes in
India. In 2014, 5 cr is 50 million. If
the number of illegal Bangladeshi
infiltrators in India in 2014 was 50
million, today it may be double of that
potentially double. So potentially we
may have 100 million illegal
Bangladeshes in India. This this dwarfs
what Europe is facing.
This is Europe is facing nothing
compared to what we are harboring.
So what are we doing about this?
That's the real question.
If Europe is facing this and we are
worried about their their future, what
about our future?
We are facing
a problem that's orders of magnitude
worse than what the Europeans are facing
and we are not even aware of it.
We're not even aware of it. I don't know
where India is going really. How many
Bangladeshes have been have we deported
in the past decade? I wonder what are we
doing?
Bala Gi says, I found most of the
Christians in Goa defend the Goa
Inquisition. Mukunda says, do mind that
most Goan Christians defend the barbaric
inquisition and don't forget the best
breast rippers that Francis Xavier used.
So I discussed this in a previous uh
episode, right? The Goa Inquisition. I
discussed this in detail. uh the
barbarity, the atrocities, the the
inhuman practices of the Christian
missionaries and and this person Francis
Xavier who brought the Inquisition into
India all of that and and it's
interesting that most Goan Christians
they defend the Inquisition
which was applied to their own
ancestors.
So why was the Inquisition applied in
Goa brought into India brought into Goa?
Because the Indians, the Hindus who the
Portuguese had converted to
Christianity, they were secretly
practicing Hinduism.
So the Portuguese brought in the
Inquisition
and they proceeded to brutalize the hell
out of the Hindus and they have burned
the records of the institution which
means we will never know how many lacks
of Indians they killed
and tortured and how many people's hands
were chopped off and whatn not.
must be in the tens or hundreds of
thousands. They've destroyed the records
of their atrocities and brutalities
because it must be horrific.
And then they brutalized the the
converts so badly that they became
proper zealous converts. They had no
choice but to become proper militant
Christians and their descendants are the
Christians of Goa today. So that
zealousness,
zealatry, whatever you want to call it,
has been passed down over the
generations. So they defend their
oppressors.
They defend the evil people who brutally
converted their ancestors
from their original
civilizational belief system
to this foreign religion.
See when the slave takes up the whip and
whips himself then the master's job is
done. So that's what we have in India.
Deeply deeply mentally colonized people.
They these people know what was done to
their ancestors and they still defend
it. Imagine the amount of mental
colonization and mental slavery these
people have. It's terrible. That's what
India is dealing with.
And not just the Goans, even ordinary
Indians are deeply mentally colonized
and they're not they're not even aware
of it.
Right. Um [snorts]
let's see what I have a whole bunch of
other questions. Let's take some more
interesting questions. Okay. Uh Somi
says, "I have seen that whenever someone
points out that America is a stolen land
on Twitter, a lot of white people gloat
about it in in saying that it was
conquered and the natives were
univilized wararm mongers. What was
America like before the whites came in
1500 1492?" Yeah, that's when
Christopher Columbus stumbled into the
Americas and he imagined he had finally
discovered India. Columbus was looking
for India and he ended up discovering
for the white people the Americas. Now
what was what was the continent like
before the whites came in? And is it
true that the you know what the what the
whites say that the the natives were
barbarians who were constantly fighting
each other, killing each other,
murdering each other, always doing
warfare. They never built anything of
any importance and that's why they were
inferior savage barbarians who had to be
civilized by the superior whites. That's
what the narrative on Twitter is and
very prominent people espouse this
narrative.
Now the the question is this claim that
they make that the native Americans were
barbarous. They were always at war with
each other, always killing each other.
Where does this narrative come from? It
comes from the records written by the
Europeans in the European invaders.
Now the European invaders will do their
best to justify
their brutal barbaric
conquest of the land
won't they?
If you are, if you do something like the
Portuguese when they did the Goa
Inquisition,
eventually they they burned all the
records of the of the Inquisition. Just
a few records survived in in Rio the
Janeiro. Everything else was burned
because what they did was incredibly
brutal and horrific, genocidal.
So they had to hide the evidence of
their atrocities. Similarly, the Americ
the the European colonizers, the
European occupiers of the Americas, they
wrote
records and and and and
testimonies
to justify
their brutal invasion and occupation of
the Americas and their large scale
genocide of the natives. So, you have to
say that, right, to justify what you're
doing that these people were barbarians.
They were killing each other. So, we put
an end to the killing.
>> [clears throat]
>> You will, you know, see these records
from the Spaniards for example in Miso
America that the Aztecs,
okay, they were brutal people. They
practiced large scale human sacrifice.
They had this pyramids on which they
would have these horrific sacrificial
displays of human sacrifice. They would
take a knife and cut a man's heart out
and throw the body there and they killed
millions of people like that. That's
what they claim. That's what they claim.
You know what happened during the French
Revolution?
How many thousands of people were were
killed in the same manner in public? If
an Aztec person were to visit Europe or
France and Paris at the time, would he
not say that the Europeans were
bloodthirsty barbarians who sacrificed
people
for whatever reason? When the Europeans
were burning witches alive, if an Indian
were to go there, what would that Indian
person see? And what would the Indian
person recount that the Europeans do
human sacrifice
for their religion
and the Europeans hate women? That's
what they would say. Now the question is
how many
um people were sacrificed? Let's say
it's a sacrifice. Okay? How many
uh persons
did the Aztecs
sack
sack re
sacriice per year let's see what this
this uh
what the AI has to say uh estimates
ranging from a few hundred to tens of
thousands
okay best estimate
best estim estimate
what's the best estimate
common estimate 1,000 to 20,000 now how
many people are executed uh in in China
every year how many people are ex let's
see okay how many people were executed
how many people
were executed in England
per year
in the 1700s S let's see
100 per year 6,000. So once again we
don't have the exact number bloody code
during the a during the 1600s. Let's see
1600s what do we have?
Um
okay 25 to 30 but 10 100,000 people and
so on.
So the point is maybe the Azik were were
simply executing war criminals or or war
captives or maybe criminals once a year
you bring them out. We don't know but
the Spanish said that these were all
ritual sacrifices, human sacrifices.
The the Europeans committed human
sacrifices. I mean public executions are
human sacrifices.
So you can portray any culture as
bloodthirsty, barbaric. I mean look at
the way India has been portrayed. He
forced millions of women allegedly
to burn themselves alive per year.
That's what they claim about us which is
an utter lie.
Sati was incredibly rare. Incredibly
rare. But the the common portrayal today
on Twitter about India is that our
ancestors burned their women alive
routinely.
So these stories are all you know
fabrications. I don't believe them. Now
what kind of land was America before the
whites arrived?
It was a prosperous land.
The after the whites arrived about 90%
of the population was genocided in
variety of ways. Some of it was because
of European diseases. Some of much of it
it was because of just massacres and
murders.
But more than 90% of the population was
genocided across the Americas wherever
the Europeans um
you know captured the territory. So you
had
vast civilizations,
very advanced civilizations. The Aztecs,
the Misoamericans, they discovered zero
independently of India about 2,00 2,000
years ago. They had calendars that went
back hundreds that went back that could
tell you astronomical events centuries
in the future. They had sophisticated
poetry. They had their own education
system. They had their own bureaucracy.
That's the Aztec, the Triple Alliance
Empire around Mexico City, Tenotlan. It
was a vast metropolis.
Imagine Venice with its canals, but a
thousand times larger. That sort of
thing. They were very sophisticated. Um,
down south in in
present day Peru, etc., You had the Inca
Empire that was incredibly sophisticated
once again. They uh had their own
agricultural revolution maybe 10,000
years ago. And the Inca Empire which
emerged out of the coast of Lake
Titikaka.
It was also extremely prosperous,
incredibly sophisticated bureaucracy,
um a very homogeneous population,
uh very effective bureaucracy and and
very high levels of prosperity. All this
was destroyed by the Spaniards. In the
north,
you'll you'll be told that the natives
of North America were all barbarians.
They had big cities like Cahokia and
whatnot.
sophisticated, you know, uh,
architecture.
Uh, they had agriculture. They they had
in in North America, it's all been
destroyed.
In North America, it's it's like they
have destroyed and wiped out all all
traces of of non of pre-Uropean
civilization.
It's like it's just barren land. Um, so
it's been one of the great tragedies in
human history. what what the Europeans
did to the to the Native Americans.
Yeah. And and whatever you told about
it, it's all lies. Even we know the kind
of lies they still tell about India.
They did the same to the Native
Americans.
Yajjnalia says, "What was the Mori
genocide and how did the pacifism
adopted by Moris in the 16th century aid
the occurrence of this genocide?"
the Mori genocide. Well, that's
well that's something we don't really
discuss a lot. So, we're talking about
Oceanania. Let's go to the map and let's
figure out where exactly is the place
we're talking about. So, let's put the
map on the screen. We are right now
centered on India. Let's go eastwards.
Let's do Let's go eastwards and into the
southern hemisphere. We are in Australia
now. Let's go further eastwards. Now we
have New Zealand. Let's go further
eastwards of New Zealand. Let's zoom in.
So if you look at the map of New
Zealand, to the east of New Zealand, we
have Cham Island.
Okay, Chitham Island. And this group of
islands around Cham Island, it's called
the Chaum Islands. And it is here that
you had a group of people roughly 2,000
in number who were called the Moriori.
They were a Polynesian people. Okay.
According to their oral records, they
their ancestors came from eastern
Polynia somewhere in this region. Okay.
And they were genetically and culturally
related to the Mauies who who are one of
the major you know indigenous who are
the indigenous population group of New
Zealand. So in the 1800s the Mauies
decided you know the Maues were were up
against European colonization. English
British colonization and the Mauies were
fighting each other and the Mais are a
very warlike people very very you know
bleos warlike people so two Maui clans
let's say or two Maui Maui tribes they
they hijacked a British vessel ship and
they sailed to Cham Island and they
landed on the island and they proceeded
to enslave the people, the Mori people.
The Mori people were about 2,000 in
number. So the Maui arrive over here and
they declare that this land is now ours
and you are our property. You are our
slaves. And the Muriori people, okay,
now that you understand the geography
etc. Let's talk about what exactly
happened here. So the Mori people, they
were a pacifistic society, very Gandhian
society. A few centuries ago, the Mori
were also fighting each other. So one of
the great Mori chieftains he said that
you know what we need to stop fighting
each other. We need to have this moral
code of nonviolence. Whatever disputes
we have we have to resolve them through
nonviolent means. Maybe ritual battle or
something but no actual violence.
And from then onwards for a couple of
centuries two three centuries the
moriori became entirely pacifistic
entirely nonviolent.
Okay. So no matter what happens you have
to be nonviolent. That was the that was
their code. Now the Maui arrive who are
maybe 800 900 and the Moruri are 2,000.
So the Mori outnumber the Maui is 2 to1
more than 2 to1. But they decided that
we will not abandon our our code of
nonviolence. We will not fight the Maui.
So the Maui and so when the Maui arrived
and enslaved a number of people, the
remaining Mori went to some part of the
island and had a big conference. What
should we do? They all gathered together
in large numbers and they decided we
will remain nonviolent. But the Maui saw
that they are gathering in a large
number and they interpreted that as a
challenge. So they went and massacred a
few hundred of them and they brutalized
the rest of the Mori. They imposed
humiliating and genocidal conditions on
the Mori that you can't speak your own
language anymore. You can't have
children with other Mori. That sort of
thing. So by the 1850s or something this
happened 1830s to 1850s 1860s and by
1930 there was only one pure blood
Moriori person left and that was it. So
today you have people of Mori ancestry
but who also have mixed Maui ancestry
and this is kind of recognized as a
genocide. So the pacifism that the Mori
Mori people had you know in part of
their ethical code or whatever that did
not cause the genocide but it
contributed to the conditions that that
that aided uh the the Maui conquest of
their land. If they had fought back the
Maui perhaps would not have won and
would not not have potentially enslaved
them. But they chose not to fight back.
It was like Tibet
a century later, right? The the Tibetans
did not really fight the Chinese. The
Chinese walked in. They had a small army
and they don't really put up much of a
resistance.
So that's the mori genocide. You know vi
nonviolence. This is what happens when
you are like you know committed to non
nonviolence no matter what happens.
Swami says, "Can you talk about the
harrying of the north? Why were there no
consequences and no generational
hatred?" What is the harrying of the
north? We're talking about English
history.
The harrying of the north happened in
the 11th century
in the winter of 1069 1070.
The year 1069 1070.
What is the what are we talking about
here? So in the year 1066 1066
the Duke of Norm okay let's let's let's
go to the map
uh where's map here's the map so we're
talking about England here uh the
northwest portion of France it's called
Normandy Normandy okay that's where you
had Vikings who settled there and they
they intermingled with the local French
people and became French Vikings Normans
so in this region you had and the and
the the first Duke of the Vikings in
Normandy was a guy called Rolo.
His greatgrandson or great great
grandson was William who was
illegitimate. Okay, so he was called
William the Bastard. He himself called
himself William the Bastard. And in the
year 1066 AD, William the Bastard landed
in Hastings with an invasion force
and he was able to defeat the king of
England, Harold, King Harold of England,
Harold Goodwinson. And that's how
William the Bastard became William the
Conqueror and conquered England. And he
became the king of England through
conquest. Now when he became the king of
England, he had to subdue the locals,
you know, the local Anglo-Saxons who had
been ruling England for a very long
time, for several centuries. He had to
subdue them. He had to he had to impose
his rule, his law on England. And he was
able to do it. But there was tremendous
resistance in the north of England in
Yorkshire. You see the city of York
here. Um it was called Yorvik by the
Norwegians by by the Vikings. So the
city of York and there is Durham
somewhere over here. Where is Durham?
Dirham. This is Dirham. Right. So in
Yorkshire and Durham there was
tremendous resistance against William.
William Williams occupation of England.
William's soldiers were killed. The
garrison of Yorkshire was destroyed and
the soldiers were killed, massacred. So
there was significant resistance against
Williams rule in the north. So in 1069
in the winter he decided to to launch a
massive military campaign in the north.
Um it was a campaign of destruction. It
was it came to be known as the harrying
of the north. So he decided that he's
going to employ scorched earth tactics
in the north. He's going to destroy the
people's crops. He's going to destroy
the people's fields. He's going to
destroy their livestock, all the all the
all the animals that they have. He's
going to kill them all. and he's going
to massacre as many people as he can.
And that's what he did. He personally
led the campaign, the military campaign.
And he devastated the north of England
all the way to from between Yorkshire
and Darham. And I don't know 100,000
150,000 people are said to have been
affected. I don't know if it means
killed or what, but maybe. So the
population of England at this time was
about 2 million and about 150,000 people
were affected. It's about almost 10% of
the people of England were affected and
the entire region north was completely
devastated. It was made unusable for
agriculture, farming, animal husbandry,
whatever. The people were were massacred
in large large numbers and for even a
decade later the place was a wasteland.
That's how that's how destructive
Williams harrying of the north was. And
the outcome was that he was able to then
impose his laws, his rule over the north
of England. He was able to replace the
local lords with the local Anglo-Saxon
lords with Norman French-speaking lords
who were who had allegiance to William.
And it is said that you could even see
the the
uh the consequences in satellite images
because the way the villages are spaced
apart today uh they are spaced about
very evenly almost mathematically which
is very unusual and very artificial. So
the whole place apparently was so badly
devastated that the villages had to be
uh refounded
in a certain way that essentially is is
still visible from satellite images. If
you are a trained historian, you'll be
able to figure out what exactly was the
consequences of what William did. So
that's uh William the Conqueror's
harrying of the north. From his
perspective, it was a necessary act. He
tried his best to subjugate the north,
but they resisted. So that's why he had
to resort to brutal force and by through
brutal force he succeeded. Um why were
there no consequences, no generational
hatred? See, he was so powerful. His
might, his hard power like we discussed
in geopolitics was so overwhelming that
there could be no consequences. There
were no consequences. The people of the
region, they were smashed. They were
defeated badly, devastated. How can
there be consequences? Generational
hatred.
Well, over time, the Anglo-Saxons and
the Normans intermingled over centuries.
We're talking about a thousand years
ago. Over time the people intermingled
and nobody today see if you go to
England today who identifies as Norman
who identifies as Anglo-Saxon nobody.
They're all intermixed. Today you have
the original the original population was
Celtic. Then you had Roman blood that
came in during the Roman occupation of
England. Then you had the Anglo-Saxons
and the Judes who invaded from Germany
about 450 AD around that time. So then
they intermingled with the with the with
the with the Celtic people and the in
the Roman descendant people and created
a mixed population. And then you had the
Normans who invaded between the Yeah.
Then they had the Normans who came in
but before that there were the the Vik
Vikings who invaded England and and
settled in parts of England, northern
parts of England for a couple of
centuries. Then you had the Vikings the
Normans who were of Viking origin. So
today you have a very mixed population.
Nobody identifies as Saxon or Celtic or
Norman or Viking, whatever. They're all
pretty much mixed. In the north of
England, you have a different kind of
English that's spoken. The accent is
different. It's more like the, you know,
the the languages of the of of the
Nordic countries. The accent is more
like the flat wow, etc. Uh that's the
only remnant of the Viking era. But
there's no generation hatred because
everybody is mixed now. It's a mixed
mainly mixed populations.
Okay. Next.
Udith Mahesh says, "What led South
Africa to give up its nukes to other
nations? Did Israel get its nukes from
South Africa? If so, how could they
convince the South Africans to give them
nukes?" The South Africans did not give
the nukes to Israel. See the South
Africans by the 1980s had had built
about
six nuclear weapons, six nuclear
warheads. Okay. And so they had access
to to uranium mats and they were able to
make six nuclear warheads as as a
consequence of of of that. And the South
African nuclear weapons program
cooperated with the Israeli nuclear
weapons program in terms of resources,
knowhow, etc. Uh but there was no
sharing of u nuclear weapons. The South
African nukes were South African, the
Israeli nukes were Israeli. The Israeli
nukes were based on plutonium. Uh they
had the negative plant where the nukes
were where the plutonium was was bred
and the nukes were possibly
assembled there. Um the the South
African nukes were mostly most likely
uranium based nukes much larger, heavier
and so on. But there was cooperation.
There was probably one joint test
between the South Africans and the and
the Israelis. The VA incident 1979.
Let's go and Google that.
Uh and that that gave rise to the
discovery essentially of of gammaray
bursts very important in astrophysics.
Va incant
1979. So it's an unidentified event a
double flash which is a characteristic
of a nuclear explosion. Yeah. Uh it was
detected by an American VA satellite in
1979 over the South African territory
near the South African territory of
Prince Edward Island islands in the
Indian Ocean and most likely it was a
joint South African Israeli nuclear
test. These VA satellites were put in
space by the Americans to detect these
characteristic double flashes. A nuclear
explosion
if it is not bel the surface if it's a
surface explosion it has a double flash.
there's an initial very rapid burst of
of photons and gamma rays and whatnot
and then there's a slower secondary
flash. So that's characteristic of a
nuclear explosion and that's what the VA
satellite detected. The VA satellites
were put in put into space to detect
such clandestine nuclear tests but they
also ended up detecting gammaray bursts
which is a very important astrophysical
phenomenon in astrophysics. We'll not
discuss that here. So um eventually by
the 1980s the South Africans decided
that we have to now reintegrate
ourselves into into the world. Um the
cold war was winding up. Um the Cubans
were withdrawing from Angola. The Soviet
threat was almost over and South Africa
had to essentially the the Americans or
whoever must have pressurized them to
give up a path and become a normal
nation which means have a democratic
election and which means the majority
will now rule. The majority South
Africans are of obviously black people,
right? African origin people. The South
African white people are a minority who
were oppressing, subjugating and ruling
the majority people. So the Afric so the
African National Congress would come to
power. Nil Mandela would come to power
and FWD clerk and his and his people his
party they said that you know what these
nuclear warheads these weapons should
not fall into the hands of the African
National Congress and the majority
population of South Africa. So let's
dismantle these. So the nuclear weapons
were dismantled. The uranium was recast
and given to I don't know the IAE or
whatever. So it was it was disposed of
and South Africa gave up its nuclear
weapons um program. That is what
happened. It did not give the nuclear
weapons or the facile material to to to
Israel. That is not the case. Okay.
[clears throat]
Um, Amisha says, "Why did Latin die out
as a language after the fall of the
Roman Empire, but English, Spanish,
French, and Portuguese persisted in all
of their colonies after their dis
disappearance from them?" You could say
that you know what
why did Sanskrit die out in India? But
Hindi, Marathi, Punjabi,
Bengali, Gujarati, Asamis, all these
languages, what do they still continue?
The fact is all these languages that I
just mentioned here, Hindi, Marathi,
Punjabi, etc. These are all languages
that are daughter languages of Sanskrit.
They evolved out of Sanskrit. Similarly,
you have something called the Romance.
Excuse [clears throat] me. Give me a
second.
You have something called the romance
languages. Okay, let's list them
romance languages.
So which are these? Spanish, Portuguese,
French, Italian, Roman. You also have
Catalan, Roman, Sardinian.
All these languages still exist.
And these romance languages
they evolved from Latin. Wulgar Latin is
the everyday spoken language of the
Roman Empire. Languages evolve. So
English persists. But the English that
is spoken today, it's not the English
that was spoken 500 years ago.
Okay. um the English that was spoken in
England in 1,000 AD, if you were to read
that, you would not recognize a word of
it.
The English that was spoken in about
1500 AD, maybe some of it may make
sense. The English from 1700 AD, a lot
of it will make sense, but it'll still
sound quaint and and and different.
Languages evolve.
So out of old Latin wulgar Latin which
is the common language which was the
common language of the everyday language
the everyday language of the people of
of of Italy of the Roman Empire that
language even eventually evolved into
other languages
such as Portuguese, French, Catalan,
Spanish and so on so forth. Right? So
languages evolved just like Sanskrit
never really died. It still lives
in various forms from the perspective of
vocabulary and grammar in its daughter
languages. Similarly, Latin still lives
in the same way in its daughter
languages like French and Spanish and
Italian and so on so forth. Right? It
wasn't it wasn't a dis disappearance. It
was simply evolution of the language.
And because Latin was spoken in various
parts of the Roman Empire and then the
Roman Empire disintegrated then these
then these local these other various
regions the languages evolved
differently in these regions over the
centuries. That's why you have French
that is different from Italian which is
different from Spanish. But if you know
French you can kind of understand a lot
of ital Italian and Spanish.
So that's that's how it went.
[clears throat]
Um let us see some more questions.
Amisha says why were the Armenians hated
so much in the Ottoman Empire that the
genocide happened?
Okay, first of all the Armenian genocide
let's understand this. It's it was not
one single event. It it's a process that
began in the last quarter of the 19th
century. There was the first wave of
genocide was was probably in the 1880s
or something. There was a major event in
the 1890s or maybe 1890 itself and then
the it continued and then there was a
the final the final nail in the coffin
was 1915 when the major event called the
Armenian genocide happened but it was a
process that was going on. Now
[clears throat] why did this happen?
Were the Armenians hated a lot?
The Armenians
and the Greeks are the native original
inhabitants of Anatolia. Let us go to
the map and understand what we are
discussing here. See the majority of
Turkey is today's Anatolia
or today's Turkey. See this is the
nation of Turkey. Here we have Istanbul
which is the the which sits across the
the imaginary fake dividing line between
Europe and Asia. To the west of
Istanbul, you have the region that the
Romans called Trace and that is this
little little part of Turkey that is
European Turkey. And to the east, you
have Anatolia, this gigantic peninsula.
Historically, this was Greek and
Armenian. There was no Turkish person
there.
Then the Turks conquered the land and
they took over the place and they ruled
the place and so on. So the Armenians
still were able to survive during the
Ottoman Empire. They had to play pay
jizia tax and whatnot, but they were
able to survive. They were able to have
their own religion and they were also
able to play an economic role in
Anatolia and in the Ottoman Empire and
they were able to make a niche for
themselves economically and they they
became merchants and artisans and
craftsmen and so on and they became
reasonably prosperous and successful
under the weight of the Ottoman Empire
as part of the Ottoman Empire's uh
economic system. So Armenians existed
under the Ottomans. Then in the 19th
century the the the Ottoman Empire
started crumbling. Turkey started being
called the sick man of Europe. The
Ottoman Empire started crumbling. There
was decay everywhere. There were
military setbacks all over the place.
There were economic setback setbacks all
over the place. And when this happens,
you have to find somebody to blame. and
someone who's who's doing well
economically, you're going to be jealous
of them. So he start pointing fingers at
the Armenians. You are not Turks.
You are working with our enemies. You
are aiding the Russians. The Russians
and the Turks had had territorial
disputes and they had warfare. Yeah. So
you start uh accusing the Armenians of
being antinational.
You start saying that you are you're
Christians. You're not Muslims. You're
not Turks. You're working without
enemies. You are stealing our money. You
are you are wealthy. How dare you be
wealthy? How dare you be alive and so
on? So that's how it starts. So the
blame started being put on the on the
Armenians for the decline of the Ottoman
Empire. There was tremendous jealousy
towards them. And by 1915 when you had
the young Turks government, the the
triumvirate of
Enoir, Jamal and
Anir, Jamal and Talat those three, the
three Pashas
they by that time Turkey was in dire
straits. They had lost multiple military
engagements with Russia in the north.
They had aligned with Germany in the
first world war and they were being
beaten very badly. They were losing
territories that were formerly Ottoman
territories, right? Uh they lost parts
of Greece that they had occupied for a
long time. The Saloni, they called it
Salonica. Um so the empire was in freef
fall and the young Turk said that you
know what we need to be you need to we
need to shore up Turkey. We need to
ensure that there are no um traitors
within within Turkey. We need to cut
down the Armen Armenian population. They
are aiding the Russians in the north and
so on. So they decided to displace the
Armenians, put them on this forced long
marches which had no end. The objective
of these long marches was to kill them
off and that's what was done to the
Armenians. So it's not like they were
actually hated but the hate was
engineered. They were turned into
scapegoats for the decline of the
Ottoman Empire. the the Turks wanted to
find some somebody to blame for what
happened and the Armenians were this
convenient target
and that's why this happened. So the
objective was to bring the population of
Armenians down below 5% so that they
will never pose any kind of threat to to
the Turks to the Turks and the objective
was to create a Turkey only for the
Turks. That's something that even
Ataturk was aligned with. Atatur was
never involved in the Armenian genocide,
but the Armenian genocide did actually
benefit
him indirectly because it aligned with
his objective of a Turkey for the Turks.
So that's about the Armenian
genocide. [cough]
[clears throat]
Amisha again says, "What has been the
effect of alcohol on history with
regards to events and characters? How
was alcoholism viewed throughout
history? Look, alcohol alcoholism has
never been viewed positively throughout
history. No matter which culture, which
civilization, which empire we're talking
about, alcohol has never been regarded
very positively, right? Whichever
whichever place. Now, what's been the
effect of alcohol on history?
Well, I can think of one incident that
that I can recount today.
When Alexander,
Alexander the Greek, when he conquered
uh Persia and he finally conquered the
great capital city of Persia, Parshapur,
the Greeks called it Perspace.
So he finally was able to conquer
Parropolis.
And then to celebrate he gets drunk.
So Alexander gets drunk and at night in
during his drunken state he says set
fire to the city
and his troops said of course sir we'll
do it and they set fire to persipalis
the great magnificent parhapur the
capital of the Persians was burnt in one
night the morning Alexander is okay and
is horrified allegedly horrified with
what he did and the blame is then put by
Greek historians on some woman companion
of Alexander that He instigated him. So
she's to blame, not Alexander. Come on.
And it is said that if you visit Parraur
today, the ruins of Persolis, the
persons called it Para. Now you can
still see the scorch marks, the burn
marks caused by the fire that Alexander
lit. So yeah, he did this in a drunken
state. He got drunk and he ordered the
the burning of the city, the great city
of Parapur. So that's one example of the
kind of effect that alcohol can have
historically then I can recount. I'm
sure there there must be so many more.
Okay, there are so many more questions
today. Let's take one more before I go
into the live stuff. Sahaj Dang says,
"What if only taxpayers were given the
right to vote in India?"
What if only taxpayers were given the
right to vote in India? In that case,
all Indians would vote
because all Indians pay tax.
You don't believe me? Go buy something
anywhere.
Yeah. Go buy a kilo of tomatoes.
Go buy whatever, you know, something
that cost 20 rupees. There's going to be
GST on everything. Maybe if you buy
tomatoes from your local street vendor,
you may not have to pay GST. But
anything else that you buy, maybe you
order something online,
you paying GST. You paying local taxes.
What VAT tax, whatever it is. Every
single purchase you make, there's tax.
If you are buying petrol, there's tax on
it. If you have a vehicle, you're paying
road tax. Every Indian pays tax.
Income tax.
Maybe
not all everyone pays that but that
doesn't matter. If you make purchases in
the Indian in the Indian economic
system, you are automatically paying
taxes.
And your local vegetable wall, he also
pays taxes to his local
local people, he has to pay taxes,
nonofficial taxes allegedly. Everybody
pays pays taxes. That's why all Indians
have the right to vote. Even if you make
only taxpayers eligible to vote, still
all Indians have to vote because all
Indians pay taxes.
Okay, let us see what is going on in the
live chat. I can see a thousand plus
comments and 32 super chats. Yeah. Okay,
let's see. Minimalist Maverick says Musk
has given free Starlink in Iran for
regime change. Elon Musk believes in
democracy. Elon Musk believes in regime
change. We will coup whoever we want.
You can shake your fist at the sky.
That's what he has tweeted. So no
surprise. Sajjit Gokul has become a new
member. Thank you so much sir. Welcome
to the membership of the channel. Thank
you very much.
Jagjit says how to solve Pakistan issue
when the US has permanent interests.
As long as the US has an interest in
Pakistan, we can't solve the issue. The
only solution is for India to get
stronger over time.
Okay. Right now the most powerful nation
in the Indian subcontinent is the US.
It's not India, it's the US because of
American power production capabilities
and other capabilities. So as long as
the most powerful nation in the
subcontinent is the US, we can't solve
the Pakistan issue. So what's the
solution? We be we grow we become more
powerful eventually we become more
powerful than the US is in the
subcontinent. Then things may change.
Right now there is no solution to the
Pakistan issue. as long as the US is
throwing its full weight behind
Pakistan.
Right. Uh, next question. Chirat says,
"A person named David Peterson from the
Swiss VPN company ProtonVPN, I saw that,
has reportedly encouraged bypassing
digital security checks in Kashmir by
hiding his his by using his app to to
spoof to hide its true identity." So if
you see a calculator, it could be the
app the the the ProtonVPN VPN app
and then I wonder what's going to happen
if we allow Starlink.
I have said this from the very
beginning. I've been saying this for a
very long time. The government of India
will make a huge mistake if it allows
Starlink to operate in India. You can
see this David Peterson etc. the kind of
uh things they are seeing on social
media. They are saying that there is
repression or suppression or operation
or whatever in Kashmir and people um
should use ProtonVPN VPN and and use the
spoofing or or hiding masking feature to
to to mask the the ProtonVM VPN act as
something else like a calculator or
something. So this is nothing but
blatant interference in the internal
affairs of India. That is like one step
away from the attempt to change regime
in India. Right? The government of India
I'm very clear about this it should not
allow Starlink to operate in India and
should take action against people like
these David Peterson or whatever if his
company is maybe we should block his
company and and and its products its
apps in India if we can block Tik Tok we
can block ProtonVPN too he's openly
defying and challenging the the rule of
law in India something should be done
about
Rook Naluak.
Okay sir, thank you very much. Thank you
so much for your contribution.
Appreciate it.
Uh
Krishant Bordaloy says you have said
that India should be should for the next
20 years not fight any war as the US is
the most powerful in the region. You
have also said that in the next 2 three
years we could go to war with Pakistan.
If it happens will Pakistan lose
territory? See, sometimes a war is
forced upon you, right? We don't want to
fight a war, but maybe a war is forced
upon us. That that situation could
potentially happen,
right? If the Pakistanis instigate
trouble in India, I see this is the last
thing we want to see happen. But what if
they succeed in some new terrorist
misadventure in India? Then the
government of India will have to
respond,
right? It could happen sooner rather
than later.
Yeah. Um, so what if this happens is the
question. What if India goes to war with
Pakistan? Will Pakistan lose territory?
It depends on a variety of factors.
Ideally, Pakistan should lose territory.
Yeah, ideally it should lose P or maybe
it should lose Sind or something.
Uh, probably probably P. But that will
happen only if we fight a lightning
blitz creek war and we end the war in
less than 72 hours. It's definitely
possible the military of the Indian
military is fully capable of doing that.
So I can't say if war if if Pakistan
will will lose territory or not but
ideally it should the next time there is
war Pakistan should be made to pay a
much bigger price. The price of
territorial loss that's what should
happen.
Bijua says, "You said button of UK nukes
is in Washington, but do you have any
proof or strong hints?"
How will such proof be available in the
public domain, sir?
The fact that that nuclear warhead of
those nuclear warheads of the UK are
mated to American missiles. That is the
proof. Beyond that, you will get no
better proof, no more proof. Okay? So,
it's not like the UK will publish this
report. Look, this is the red button. It
is in on Trump's desk. They will this
will never be done. Right. These things
are not ever disclosed in public. Right.
[laughter]
Okay. Girish Kumawat is a new member.
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you for
becoming a member. Really appreciated.
Uh Bijua says, "What no why allies gave
Napoleon exile instead of death?"
Probably because there were a lot of
supporters of Napoleon in France. A lot
of people who truly admired Napoleon.
And if Napoleon had been executed, there
could have been, you know, chaos in
France, a rebellion
and maybe it would have been
um harmful to the interests
of the UK. So, put him in exile,
claim that you are giving him dignified
treatment, but just keeping him away so
that he can't he can't fight us anymore.
That that makes sense. And then perhaps
poison him. Maybe that's what happened.
Yeah.
Uh, Rishi Barat says, "Poster check and
hydration reminder. Thank you for the
hydration reminder. Let me drink some
more of this
transian juice." Thankfully, it is still
liquid.
Thank you for the reminder, sir. Micor
says, "Could Iran instead of being
regime changed, they could be forcibly
neutered, forced treaties, non- nuclear,
etc. by the US and Israel. Müller regime
would survive but Iran could be
partitioned into two. So the US wants to
acquire
all the resources
that Iran has and the Moolah regime will
never accept being neutered like like
you're mentioning for is for Iran to be
partitioned. You will need military
intervention. The Mullah regime will
never will never accept a partition
unless it's done by force.
Right. Um and if it's done by force then
the regime will any anyway happen
because the people seem to be fed up
with the with the regime. So it's not
feasible that it will happen this way.
U the current government of Iran will
never give up. They consider the US to
be shan
the great Satan the great shaitan. They
will never enter any any such any such
humiliating treaty with the US. They may
enter into negotiations. They even did
the JCPOA in the which Trump walked away
from. So the Iranians are willing to
negotiate but they won't accept any
humiliating conditions.
So yeah I don't see it going that way
unfortunately.
Um Sumesh Pande says can this pressure
from the US to India and China force
them to create good relations between
India and China like solving border
issues? That could happen. If the
Chinese feel that they are under
tremendous
pressure from the US and the only way to
withstand this is by mending fences with
India, then they could
somewhat involunt involuntarily
um maybe resolve the border issue with
India. We are not there yet.
But yeah, if India refuses to vasalize
itself to the US, if India refuses to
vasalize itself and Iran falls, then
China may be forced to mend defenses
with India. But it will also try and
calculate if I mend fences with India
and then India becomes a US vasal later,
what happens? That sort of thing. So
there's going to be all kinds of
calculations. It's it's pretty
complicated. But yes, eventually if the
US pressure becomes significant, the
Chinese may uh very seriously consider
resolving the border issue with India
which they have kept open deliberately.
Aries manticor says wouldn't controlled
in fighting among US vasals enrich the
US military-industrial complex if India
becomes a vasal could this also be a
possible fate?
See why do you vasalize a country? You
vaselize a country so that you can
essentially manage its resources and you
can control the resources. So let's say
a nation has a lot of oil.
So you vasalize the country, their
regime becomes your puppet and then all
the oil trade is done either to you or
through you. You always get a cut and
you control where it goes and you decide
where it doesn't go. So that gives you
not just wealth, it also gives you power
and power comes from order in that
country. If you have two vessels
fighting each other, that will cause
disorder. You will lose power. You will
lose access to resources. You will have
chaos.
So if you vaselize a country, you want
the country to be in great shape. You
want it to be orderly. You want law and
order, your law and order, etc. Right?
So it doesn't make sense for controlling
fighting for the military-industrial
complex. You create wars elsewhere not
among your vas but others whom then you
can sell weapons to.
Okay. Vin
Vinci Vinci VMA says Hindu men grow
mustache and trim their beards but
Muslims do the opposite the right right
to left. Why isn't it a deliberate
tradition? I don't know about the
Islamic traditions and Islamic um why
why the Islamic culture isn't whatever
it does. I I am no expert in that. So I
I don't know. Uh when it comes to um
writing
right to left
um yeah we write left to right, right?
But the old brahme script it could also
be written written the other way. So
these systems evolve over time. The brah
script could also be written right to
left. Yeah. It was an ambidextrous
script so to say. But now we have the
tradition for the longest time, at least
2,000 years of writing left to right.
I'm not sure why the the Arabic script
is the other way around. I haven't
studied the history, so I can't really
comment about that. And the mustache and
beards and all. I I don't know the
origins of the Islamic traditions. I
don't know. Pamire says, "Why do Native
Americans typically have brown skin
tones considering North American
angosphere have historically had cold
climates?"
Well, you see, if you go to [snorts]
Yeah, actually if you look at North
Americans and indigenous North
Americans, they have brown skin tones,
don't they? But further north, if you
look at the Inuit people who are also
Native Americans, they have pretty white
skin tones or they look more like the
Mongols.
The Mongols also live pretty far up
north and they they experience pretty
harsh climates, but they aren't white as
such, right? They aren't white. Mongols
aren't white people. They they are
brownish. You could say light brownish.
So, it's all all to do with the climate.
It's all to do with the climate and the
amount of sun that you exposure that you
get. Your skin tone is a is a is a
factor. It's a function of the amount of
sun your skin is is hit with sun
exposure is your skin is exposed to u
throughout the year. So if you go to
certain parts of Europe like the
Scandinavian nations, that's where you
have very little sun exposure and that's
where you have the whitest skins. If you
go to Mongolia, it's not like you have
English climate there. You have pretty
harsh sun sunlight a lot of the time of
the year. And the same applies to the
North American Great Plains, etc. So
that's why it made sense most likely for
the skin tones to evolve in such a way
that there was melanin not a lot of
melanin but some melanin at least like
light brown that sort of thing. So
probably that's why native Americans in
North America have brown skin tones.
When when you talk about Miso America,
Mexico, etc., it's very natural for them
to have the exact skin skin tones that
Indians have. Right?
Aries Manticor says, "Is the US a
thought? Is the US reaching hyper power
status? Can it still be called a normal
superpower with with will ASI and
quantum technology propel it into a new
class of power? And what would that be
called as new hard score? right now it's
the sole superpower. Even the Chinese
have AI. The Chinese are also doing
their best to to you know o overtake the
US technologically at least when it
comes to AI and in quantum technologies.
So the US and China perhaps could be
neck in these technologies. Maybe the US
has other technologies like UFO like
technologies that they have not revealed
and so on. Um but the US isn't that far
ahead of China technologically. where
they are far ahead completely is their
power production capabilities unmatched.
You know if the US can conquer space
through Elon Musk and SpaceX, well that
could make it a hyperpower. Right?
If by 2030 the Americans start establish
a permanent colony on the moon and by
2040 2035 2040 if they establish a
permanent colony on Mars that starts
taking them into hyperpower
realms because now they have not just an
earth-based superpower and hgemony they
you know expanding their hedgeimonyy to
to outside of the earth. So it is space
that's going to be the transformative
factor I would I would imagine. Yeah. So
I would say the US will be a hyperpower
if it neut on the planet earth if it if
it is able to neutralize China as well
as Russia in that case it becomes the
absolute hedgeimon globally that you
could call a hyperpower if that's not
the case then the US colonizing moon and
the Mars that perhaps is something you
could call a hyperpower thing.
uh died in plane crashes. Should people
in India stop being delusional,
obsessing over soft power and start
realizing that so so-called
international law is all nonsense after
Trump has shown that might is right?
Well, I have been saying this for a long
time now. You see a very prominent
intelligent people on Twitter saying the
same thing. Soft power is nothing. Hard
power is the only thing. Hard power is
what matters. I have been saying this
since 2021, haven't I? That time Indians
were harping about soft power, soft
power. The same people on Twitter are
now being you know thought leaders and
saying that hard power is all all that
matters. Hard power is all that matters.
It is high time Indians wake up to the
fact that only hard power matters. Soft
power is relevant only if you have a
hard power. If you have zero hard power,
your soft power is worth nothing. So
forget about soft power. Start building
hard power. That's what I would say.
Virin Chiharma says, "How did
untouchability come into Indian society?
It didn't happen during Muslim rule or
British rule. We must blame the
outsiders, invaders, no mistake of us."
Look, every untouchability
there see in every society there are
some issues.
You go to American society, you will see
issues there. Every society has issues.
But we Indians have this habit of self-
flagagillation. But now the question is
untouchability. No, I have never seen
with my own eyes untouchability in
practice. Never. I've never seen that.
You travel across India, you go to a
cafe, you go to a restaurant, do you
care who's serving you, what that
person's cast is?
If you're in an airport, if you're in a
train station, bus station, wherever, if
you're in a crowded street, do you care
who's touching you? Do you even bother?
Nobody cares.
It's only in some parts of India we had
these issues. And all of this happened
during the past 1,000 years of foreign
occupation. Understand
that. See
most of you have watched Harry Potter.
Harry Potter
if you have watched Harry Potter or read
the Harry Potter books you will know
that in the Harry Potter society the
wizarding society there were four casts.
Four casts
uh Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, Gryffinder and
Slytherin. Four casts. There was also
the cast of slaves which was the elves
right which was the underclass the the
hidden underclass of of wizarding
society who were oppressed who were
enslaved right now how when a kid came
went to the Hogwarts school how was
their cast determined there was a
sorting hat which will determine which
cast the boy will go or the girl will go
into. So that was the system of sorting
the new population into the four casts.
Then you have the evil guy Voldemort. So
for centuries you have the tradition of
the sorting hat and that's how based on
your merit and aptitude you go into a
certain cast. Now let's say imagine the
situation where Voldemort wins and he
destroys the wizarding traditions and he
destroys a sorting hat and Voldemort
let's say he's immortal. He will rule
for 1,000 years over the wizarding
society. Then what will happen to the
society?
How will new children determine what
cast they go into? the sorting hat is
destroyed. So then what will happen that
they are afraid of Voldemort who who's
oppressive every every family will
decide that whatever cast the dad was in
that is going to be the cast of the boy
or the girl because we have no sorting
head. So we have no choice but to now
rigidify the system because we are under
oppressive rule our our normal way of of
determining our life is gone. We have to
somehow survive. So let us now make the
cast system hereditary instead of using
the sorting hat because it's gone. And
the elves we will keep them enslaved and
we will we will treat them as
untouchables.
So when a corporation or a society comes
comes under bad leadership all kinds of
evil practices creep in
when Apple went out of Steve Jobs
control and went nearly bankrupt. Whose
fault was that? Was it the fault of the
employees of Apple or was it the fault
of the leadership?
See my dear Indian friends, you need to
learn how to think critically.
You have been conditioned mentally to
take a whip and keep whipping
yourselves. Keep blaming yourselves for
everything. Keep blaming your ancestors
for everything.
The foreigners did all this to us and
they taught us to blame ourselves for
everything. I am not condoning this or
that or whatever. I do I believe in
cast. I don't believe in cast. Why do we
still even have cast? It's because the
government mandates it. They claim we
want to annihilate cast annihilate. We
don't we don't believe in cast. But then
they require that you should have your
cast on your birth certificate on your
school living certificate and everything
and you vote based on cast. Why? They
are the ones who are perpet per perpet
per perpetuating cast because it is pol
politically beneficial. End cast.
and annihilate cast completely. That's
what I would say. That's what needs to
happen in India.
Remove all mentions of cast from all
official documents. Then see what
happens. It is your politicians who are
keeping this alive.
Just like the the foreigners introduced
all these problems in Indian society
for their own benefit, today the
politicians are keeping this alive for
their own benefit. Who suffers? We
suffer.
Sam the Gamer says, "If the US vasalizes
world, what happens to RA?" Well,
if the US vasalizes the world, can RA
stand up to the US? Well, it's going to
be very difficult for that to happen.
It's not impossible. Not impossible, but
very difficult.
Uh, Brown Leprechaun says, "Why do we
suddenly see Qatar's name everywhere?"
Qatar is has it's tried to stay stay
pretty quiet and under the radar. Qatar
is a big player.
It's it's a very very loyal minion vasal
whatever you want call of the US. What
is it what happened in DHA? The DHA
accords between the US and Taliban.
DHA
it does all kinds of it it provides all
kinds of very important services to the
US. So it's not surprising to see
Qatar's name in various places. Okay. Uh
I would I would like to request
everybody please stop taking super chats
because otherwise this will go on
forever and uh we need to end maybe at a
reasonable time. So
so please please stop taking super
charts. Now I obviously dispose of all
the remaining super chats like almost 30
of them. Okay. Aries Mandor says a
thought experiment. India can only
progress with the proven path. Shadow
dictatorship masquerading is a robust
democracy hard to find and hidden like
the Americans. Your thoughts this on
this way? Well, it's worked for the
Americans, isn't it? And for the
Chinese, an open dictatorship has
worked. And the Americans say that
Russia is also dictatorship. But
whatever it is, it is working. The only
path that actually works is some form of
dictatorship, political stability, full
control. That's the only path that
works. If you go down that road of
democracy, you're digging your own
grave. Every democracy has failed or is
failing. Look at the EU nations. What
what what has democ democracy given
them? They are all right now in the
process of digging their graves.
So I agree.
I agree.
Uh Maka says give Trump the Exon Mobile
peace prize already. I would say give
him all the peace prizes. I I'll create
a new peace prize and give it to Trump.
Please sir, take it. Enjoy. Stop
destabilizing the world. But it it won't
make any difference. He wants all of
that but he also wants to grab gobble up
the entire world.
Virihma says in this nature many animals
are killed untimely by other animals.
Why is nature going against its design?
Is there any scientific reason behind
it? In this nature many animals are
killed untimely by other animals. Why is
nature going against its design? is then
if an animal kills another animal, that
animal that is killed is going to die
what we could perhaps call from a human
perspective an untimely death because if
the violence was not perpetrated on it,
it would have lived until so and so age.
But this is the design of nature.
You have predators and you have prey and
all of this exists in a balance. The
predators ensure that the prey the prey
animals don't multiply into too large a
number and don't overrun the earth. A
balance is needed.
And nature is pretty brutal.
Nature is full of violence.
Violence on various scales. You have
tigers eating large animals. You also
have little wild cats eating little
little creatures, squirrels and whatnot.
That's also pretty brutal if you see it.
Nature is is violent.
Nature is not a hins. It's not
nonviolent. It's not all peaceful.
Nature is brutal. Nature is nature is
unforgiving. This is the design. This is
the design. This is evolution. Survival
of the fittest.
This is nature. This is this is nature.
This is the design.
Aries Manticor says, "I see our people
waking up to chhatria after goddess Kali
reminds us of how ruthless the illegals
will be. It would not be pleasant at
all."
I suppose so. Perhaps I would say before
any of this happens, the government of
India should get it get its act together
and deport all illegal infiltrators.
I'm not saying deport any legal illegal
um immigrants to India. If you have come
through the proper legal channels
getting a visa and whatnot, you're
welcome to stay as long as the va v visa
allows you. Those who have broken Indian
law and infiltrated in in entered India
illegally, thus doing a criminal act,
those people have to be deported. That's
just law. So the government, what is it
doing? Do it. Please get rid of these
people. Deport them legally. I'm not
saying beat them or whatever. No need to
use violence. Just deport them all.
I don't know why it's not being done.
Uh Aries Montor says, "How brutal were
the witch trials? I see many in the new
generation of the US taking talking
about bringing it back. Jenzi is being
actively radicalized towards more alt
alt-right conservative values. Why is
this? I have no idea really. I I I
wasn't aware of this." Okay, in case
that's happening,
are people in the US talking about
bringing witch trials back?
Well, that's a very Christian thing to
do, I would say. Yeah. The witch trials
were absolutely brutal. Absolutely
brutal. the the the most popular book in
Europe for or the second most popular
book in Europe for several centuries was
the Malus Malfearum, the Hammer of the
Witches, which was a manual about how to
identify somebody, a woman who is a
witch or a person who is a witch and how
to make them confess and how to execute
them. Absolutely brutal stuff. So, you
make them confess through torture. One
way of doing it is to um tie
heavy stones to a woman's ankle and legs
and immerse her in water.
And if she floats despite the stones
being tied to her legs, it means that
she is supernatural and she's a witch,
which means she must be killed. And if
she drowns, then the poor lady was not a
witch. Thank God. I mean, what the hell?
And then if somebody was identified as a
witch, they would typically be be burned
alive or they would have some other
horrific treatments, you know, tortures
before killing and all absolutely brutal
stuff.
Okay. Prashant Taman Prash Prasham Taman
Tamahhan says after hearing the reports
of US Department of Justice that
Pakistan paid 5 million to to stop
operation Sindor if Porters can be
bought why are we paying this game
playing this game in hard mode we tariff
our economy is 8% with tariff or economy
is 8% without it would be 10%. Okay,
I've not seen this report that Pakistan
paid $5 million to stop operations in
Sindur.
For the US, $5 million is not even
peanuts. It's nothing.
The US intervened, interfered, whatever
you want to call it, not because
Pakistan paid them money.
They interfered because they are on
Pakistan's side. They have always been
on Pakistan's side. They want to use
Pakistan as a counterbalance to India.
It has nothing to do with money.
If Pakist some Pakistani if the
Pakistanis hired some lobbyist and paid
some money to that person, it's not that
what that that stopped operation zindur.
Okay. Um and if we employ lobbyists and
if we give $100 million to the US, they
will still work against us. It has
nothing to do with money. It's something
to do with much more than money. It's
about control of the world. Money is not
going to solve the issue.
Uh, Slendy says, "What are short-term
objectives and long long-term end goals
of the deep state for the whole world?"
Look, short-term objectives, whatever is
happening right now, we can see the
short-term objectives playing out in
real time. The long-term end goal is
global domination,
one world government.
The deep state, whatever you want to
call it, let's call it the deep state.
It will the objective is to rule the
entire world and control every single
person. That is the end goal and to do
that you have to take various actions
and put the pieces in place in the
jigsaw puzzle which is what's happening
right now.
Dian plane crash says what's your
opinion on Igor Girkin X FSB who downed
the Malaysian Airlines 17 founder of
Angry Patriots Club Putin incompetent
and asked for his resignation. I am not
aware of this person.
I'm not aware of this angry patriots
club. I am not aware of
somebody calling Putin in incompetent
etc. I'm not aware of this sigor
giri girkin. Uh sorry I'm not aware of
this person.
Slendy's says what will life be like for
a child born today into a family that's
part of the deep state?
I suppose a life of privilege.
Right? All doors open for you.
If you are let's say Indian and you are
born in a wealthy family, you still have
to apply for visas whenever you go for
various part of the world. If you are
born into that family, everything I
suppose everything opens for you. Your
you know life of luxury, life of
privilege, life of access,
life of endless opportunities, that sort
of thing I suppose. Yeah.
died in plane crash says will Trump's US
make move against the hermit kingdom I
don't think so the hermit kingdom not
which is North Korea not only has
nuclear weapons it has the means to
deliver them and deliver them across the
Pacific
[clears throat]
uh Trump's US will not make a move
against the hermit kingdom see they have
bought their security and sovereignty
through nuclear weapons and the means to
deliver them.
Ru Jen George says, "Can you share all
what resources do you read regularly to
catch up on geopolitics and history like
magazines, newspapers and all?"
Um,
I don't read newspapers. I don't read
magazines. Uh, most of the information,
history, look for history, you read
books. You read books for history. Uh
you don't read history. No, of course.
If something you want something
additional from what you've read in the
book, you what I I typically do is I
read uh research papers, academic papers
uh related to archaeology or or or or
genetics or whatever. So that's
something I would do for history. For
geopolitics, I read online publications.
I don't watch television. I don't read
newspapers. I don't read mag read
magazines. I get most of my information
online just you know look at everything
from 360 360deree perspective. Read the
New York Times, read the CNN, read Fox
News, read foreign policy, read the
diplomat, uh read the Chinese Shinoa,
read uh Deutsch Chaveel,
the Indian publications which
essentially just echo the West. Read the
Korean Yonhap
news agency. Read Nikai, read the
straight times, everything, okay? And
look at what's what people are saying on
social media, on Twitter and so on. So
that way you get an idea of what
everybody is saying. Then if you have
your own orientation, your own
perspective, you'll be able to figure
out what actually is happening in the
world. So that's kind of what I do, sir.
Um,
yeah, that's that's that's how I do it.
Akash Sudhar says, "Is Turkey also a
Vasal state?" Yes sir, it is. It is.
It's a very ambitious one. It knows how
to play the game, but it is still a
vasal.
One example of the Vasal Horde I can
give you is look, let's let's do it
together. Okay, let's do it in real
time. All of us, let's go to Google.
Let's ask this question.
Does Turkey
host US nuclear
weapons on on its territory?
Yes sir or no sir. Yes sir.
You see Turkey hosts US nuclear weapons
about 20 tactical nuclear bombs at
Inurik air base as part of NATO's
nuclear sharing program.
Um these weapons remain under sole US
control and require US authorization to
use. This is the signature of a vasal.
Okay. And I can give you lots of other
examples but here's a classic example of
a nation that's a vasal.
Akashtar. Thank you sir for what you do.
Thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Thank you for the support and thank you
for the contribution to the to the
channel. Thank you very much.
Sedat Singh Rajpur Hoit says what could
be India's
strategy to resist America uh American
arm twisting and remain sovereign and
how can I contribute now as a student I
want to join the air force
India's strategy to resist American arm
twisting
is to find allies or partners who will
have similar objectives those allies or
partners can be Russia and China I
suppose who else stands now Iran Iran
may soon fall. I don't know. Is it still
there?
Only RA if they come together can stand
up together together to the US.
Individually they'll fall one by one. Um
and India should find a way to keep
growing economically. Yeah. And India
should ideally find its own oil
reserves.
These are the things India can do. What
can how can you contribute as a student?
You want to join the air force? Well, if
you join the air force, you can
contribute. If you want to contribute in
other ways, well,
excel in whatever you're doing in life,
right? Become wealthy, use the wealth to
help the nation in some way. There's
plenty of things you can do as a student
right now. You can't do a thing. You can
do a thing if you become a person of
substance.
So, spend the next 20 years becoming a
person of substance. Okay? Spend the
next 20 years investing in yourself.
Spend the next 20 years being selfish.
Then when you are a person of substance,
maybe you have a hundred billion
dollars. I wish you that. Then you can
help the country in a more substantial
way. That's what you what you should do.
So don't be impatient. Don't be in a
hurry to contribute. Contribute once you
are a person of substance. All the best.
Sad
Rukalak
says, "Can you comment on pre-Islamic
goddesses alat?" I am not aware of I I
know the name Alat. I know that there
were multiple goddesses. I know that in
Mecca there was this temple with
polytheistic temple with multiple gods
and goddesses. uh but I don't know their
their their
you know what the goddesses signified
what their function was and what the
polytheistic pantheon was like I don't
know I'm not aware so I can't possibly
comment on this sorry about that
says leftists in India often argue that
even if Indians had unal alived all
British in India then Britain would have
invaded India again and colonized us
yeah how would They do that if we had un
if if our ancestors had unalived them
all and if our ancestors had unalived
them all. Don't you think they would be
capable of unaliving more of them?
Leftists have no actual logic.
Okay. They only have an agenda. They
only have falsehood to pedal. Especially
Indian leftists. So
BJA says how why Holy Roman Empire was
called. So it was neither Holy nor Roman
nor really an empire.
Uh the Holy Roman Empire. It was based
in Germany, wasn't it? Carolus. No. Who
was it? Um I think it was controlled by
the Vatican. That's why it was holy. It
was not holy of course by its actions.
It was pretty nasty. It was not Roman.
It was based in Germany mostly. Yeah.
And it was kingdom but it was see
anything can be called an empire, right?
um anything you can call an empire. I
mean they speak about the ona empire
which is a little kingdom of the Richard
the Lionheart and so but they call it an
empire. So if you have an inflated sense
of your importance you will call
whatever your your people did as an
empire.
Uh yeah so that's see it's a very
euroentric perspective. You're right. It
was it wasn't holy. It wasn't Roman. It
was more German than Roman and it was a
kingdom more than an empire. So you're
right on all these fronts.
Uh Amisha says, "Freedom at midnight.
Should I read this book? Is it Salman
Rushi?" Let me just double check that.
Freedom at midnight
book.
Oh, it's by Dominique in Larry Collins.
I haven't read this so I can't comment.
Um if it's a white man or white men who
wrote it, Indians will obviously give
very good reviews. As you can see, it's
got a 4.5 rating on Amazon India. Uh I I
don't know really. I haven't read this.
I haven't read it. It seems to have a
good rating. Maybe you can perhaps if
you feel so inclined, read it. I haven't
read it so I I can't say. Sorry.
Krishant Bordaloy says, "If Pakistan
loses land to us in war, will the US
force us to give back the land or will
they place economic sanctions or will
they tell us that we are intolerant to
minorities?" Look, if they tell us this
or that, it doesn't matter. What they
actually do is what matters. Their
words, who cares, will the US force us
to give back the land? They may try to
do that. Will they place economic
sanctions? They most likely will place
economic sanctions. Yeah. So if you play
big boy games, you're going to have big
boy consequences too.
So you need to have the appetite to play
the game and you need to be aware of the
consequences.
So if the consequences if if the
benefits outweigh the consequences, then
you can go ahead and do such things.
Yeah. But the US will definitely try
their best to force us first of all to
not take the land. But if we take the
land, they may try and force us to give
it back or they may put economic
sanctions and try to strangulate India's
economy. These things are very much in
the offing for sure.
James J says, "If India is so great, why
can't it capture Antarctica?" See, India
isn't that great today. Okay. When we're
talking about greatness here, what is
the what is the definition of greatness
you're talking about? We're talking
about hard power. So if you want me to
issue a reminder of what our hard power
is like from India's perspective, take a
look at this. This this ranking scale
still stands. The US hard power score is
93. Russia 54, China 15, India is
slightly less than five. As you can see,
India is not that great from a hard
power perspective. India was great in
the past. It was great culturally,
civilizationally. It was great as a as
whenever we had major empires in India
like the Morian Empire, the Kushan
Empire, the Gupta Empire, the Chola
Empire, the Marata Empire. But right now
we are not that. We have a hard power
score of 4.91
and we can't even reunify the Indian
subcontinent at this point in time.
These are just facts.
And we have India I don't think has any
ambition of capturing Antarctica. So
[laughter]
anyhow good to see you James the trader
says your podcast with Vishal Malhotra
about Nehu Gandhi doubt ruling for 50
plus years Vishal Malhotra that's a long
time ago okay ruling for 50 plus years
with worst policies by the party why US
sponsored terror to Pakistan and India
if we aren't performing well at the time
see it's not whether we are per whether
we were performing well or not it is
what India's potential is even when
India was was limping along with the
Nehuvian rate of growth 2% per year 3%
per year even then if India
changed its policies India would had the
potential to grow very rapidly and
become a very powerful nation even today
India has the potential to be a very
powerful nation so the Pakistani angle
is because it the US understood India's
potential
that someday maybe in the next 6 months
if a new leader comes in India and
implements all the right policies and
gets the nation on track India will very
rapidly become a very powerful nation
and that's why they kept Pakistan as a
counterbalance and that's why they
always kept Pakistan on the offensive
against India through terrorism and
whatnot that is the reason why
fast snail says if India I love the name
fast snail if India exits the quad
and improves India China relations. The
Quad is mostly dead now. The Quad is
mostly dead. The Americans are
supporting Pakistan against India.
In that situation, how will the Quad
exist?
Right? The Quad is dead. The Quad is in
on is on ice. You have Pax Silica. You
have other things now. The Americans are
no longer talking about the Quad. So, we
don't have to officially exit the Quad.
just put just stop attending quad mate
meetings or if there's a quad meeting
send a junior minister or a junior
diplomats to attend it that's it right
uh will this improve India China
relations while the only thing that can
India improve India China relations is
how much pressure the Americans apply on
China that is what will determine
whether India China relations improve or
not if the Chinese come under intense
pressure from the US they will probably
decide that you know let's let's mend
fences with India And the way to do that
for China by the way if Chinese people
are listening it's to resolve the border
issue the undemarcated India Tibet
border which China has refused to
demarcate for decades. That is the core
issue.
Okay. Agent Ford says does the British
crown hold power over India till date? I
doubt it very much. I doubt it.
uh there are there are there has been
speculation that there may have been
some secret clauses in the India
independence act or whatever but uh I am
not aware of those and I doubt if I
doubt that the British crown still holds
any kind of power or India
Golhaha says Iran will become a puppet
state why are Indians celebrate
celebrating I don't understand what are
my thoughts from so from India's
perspect perspective it will be a bad
thing because now you will have a second
Pakistan west of Pakistan if Iran
becomes a US puppet
then it is also aligned with the with
the US just the way the Pakistan is
aligned and that's bad for India we lose
Chabahar we lose the relationship we
have with Iran currently and Pakistan
gets a very major ally right you may
even have US troops in Pakistan occupied
Kashmir as a consequence
so Indians obviously don't understand
the way things work many of them unless
they watch the ch this channel the ones
who don't watch watch this channel will
be celebrating some of them are saying
that you know what uh the US coup in
Venezuela is is actually good for India
I don't know on what basis these experts
have concluded that the US regime change
in Venezuela has has actually had a good
effect on India or it's going to be good
for India in the long run I don't get it
how there's all kinds of people who are
misleading Indians let's say through
their uh
analysis And that's why Indians are
perhaps celebrating this. It's stupid.
Bijuya says, "Recommend some interesting
books on economics." No, economics is
not my thing. I I don't know. I can't
recommend books on economics. Sorry.
Uh Anu Jayen says, "Does MK Gandhi have
any connection with MI6?" Well, he's
dead, so he can't have any connection.
But did he have connections?
Well, if Mr. Gandhi had connections with
the MI6, did the MI6 exist back then?
Let me see.
Did the MI6 exist in the 1940s? Let's
see. Did MI6 exist in
uh World War let's say 1930?
Uh yes it did exist. It's its
predecessor organization existed. So
yeah the organization that would become
the MI6 did exist back then. Did Mr.
Gandhi have connections? Well, if there
were any connections, we don't know
about those. U if there were
connections, the British would have
records of those, but they will never
never make those public. So, yeah. We
for says, "Thank you for all your
efforts." Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you very much indeed.
Fast snail says, "If NATO done, is NATO
done if Greenland happens? Does the US
care?" NATO is mostly done if if
Greenland happens. NATO is mostly done.
Yeah, maybe that's what the US wants.
Maybe the US has decided that we'll take
over Greenland and that helps us kill
two birds with one stone. We also get to
end NATO so that we can now micromanage
each nation one- on-one and have an even
better effect than we had with NATO by
dealing with each of these nations
oneon-one. That way we'll be able to
control them even better. So yeah, if
Greenland happens, NATO is done.
Kedar Bhatt says, "Do you think religion
plays a major role in geopolitics as the
world seems to be against Hinduism since
the invasion till now?" Why is that?
Well, the West hates Hinduism.
Hinduism is the only old polytheistic
religion that still stands. It's the
oldest civilization on on the planet
that we know of. The longest
continuously existing culture and
civilization in the world. and uh the
religion that the west now has it's a
it's been able to
end the the original religion of the
west you know the polytheistic tradition
of the west were were all destroyed but
India somehow still stands that's why
they hate it that's why they still
that's why they hate Hinduism uh does
religion play a major role it does play
a significant role yeah certain
religions especially the Abrahamic
religions are political religions
they are religions of control and power.
They are religions of command and
control
and these religions can be leveraged or
utilized for geopolitical or political
purposes. So, religion does play certain
religions play a major role in
geopolitics. I I think it's very obvious
which religions these are. Hinduism is
not one of those because Hinduism is
Hinduism is not a an organized religion.
It doesn't have the top- down military
command and control structure. That's
why Hinduism is kind of irrelevant
geopolitically because it's more
civilizational than religious. Right?
Vir Kamat says why is North Korea not
fully sovereign according to you?
Because it is completely dependent on
China on because of so many things. It
is constrained by its dependence on
China.
See it has nuclear weapons. It can
deliver the nuclear weapons, but it
still needs the benevalent protective
shadow of the Chinese state for its
long-term survival.
And that's why it's not fully sovereign.
Yeah. When you are constrained by your
external dependence on another nation or
another set of nations, that's when you
are not fully sovereign.
Um, and [clears throat]
most likely the Kim dynasty has stayed
in power because of Chinese help. I
don't think they can stay stay in power
on their own. The the North Korean
military has so many soldiers, so many
generals, so many officers, right? Why
do they all
um you know
pay their allegiance
to the Kim dynasty because of China
right that's so that's why North Korea
is not fully so sovereign uh Krishna
Bordal says when west turns right wing
it becomes extremely conservative and
brutal to women when we are becoming
more right wing we are becoming more
liberal truly goes to show what society
was really which society was really more
free clearly absolutely clearly
No question about it. Um,
[clears throat]
yeah, I mean I have nothing to add to
this. You're absolutely right.
When Christian societies become
conservative or other societies become
Christian conservative, right-wing, they
they oppress their women, right?
But in in our case, it's the other way
around. So it tells you which societies
were actually more free. No question. No
question about that.
Avid Kumar, thank you very much, sir.
Thank you very much indeed.
YT user says, "My American friend says
before them, the natives didn't have a
country and used to fight among
themselves." Same old story. Same old
story. We discussed that. And they also
did the same thing in nothing wrong.
Conquer and rule was the law of the
time.
Yeah. But don't then don't portray
yourself as the as the world's defenders
of human rights and democracy and all
that.
Right. See the as we can see today in
geopolitics
all that matters is hard power.
So then don't claim that the they were e
they were evil. They were fighting each
other. They didn't have a country. They
had their own way of living. The nation
state system came from the west.
The American natives did not have that
system. They had a different system,
their own indigenous system that is none
of your business. But you people
destroyed it and you people genocided
the natives. And now you claim that they
were backward, they were primitive, they
were wararmongers and that's why it was
important to civilize and Christianize
them. Stop
doing this fake justification. Be very
open about the fact that you are
imperialist and you genocided a whole
continent. That's that's the right thing
to do. I would say it shows that there
is some guilt somewhere somewhere back
in their psyche.
Dilly print died in plane crash says is
it possible that India has missiles that
can reach Washington DC but GOI doesn't
want to reveal these also your opinion
on recent defense acquisitions and
suffic successful tests is it possible
that India has ballistic missiles that
can reach Washington but the government
doesn't reveal these it is entirely
possible
it's uh entirely possible yeah but we
don't talk about these we don't reveal
these um [clears throat] my opinion on
recent defense acquisitions in the
successful tests. I'm not aware of the
specific acquisitions, but the
successful tests are great. India has
one of the most advanced
missile programs in the world. Yeah. And
the tests prove that. So very good and
very happy to see those tests. The ones
over the Bay of Bengal, the Indian Ocean
extended all all the way into the
southern Indian Ocean. Good to see that.
Absolutely.
I am Koshik says, "Will China overtake
the US's number one superpower?" Not
going to happen. Absolutely not. No, no,
no, no. And USChina war incoming in next
5 to 10 years. And how do you see India,
China, US, etc. in the next 5 to 10
years?
First of all, China is not going to
overtake the US as number one
superpower. It's not even number two
superpower. It's not even a superpower.
It is much weaker than even Russia.
Okay? US China war incoming in next 5 to
10 years. Doubtful. The Americans want
to win without fighting a war with
China. If there is a war, there will be
a war in Taiwan. If the Chinese are
stupid enough to to make a move on
Taiwan and America will turn Taiwan into
China's Ukraine.
Uh how do I see India US China in the
next 5 10 years?
Hard to say. Hard to say. The US will be
the sole hedgeiment for the longest
time. India India will be very lucky if
it doesn't get vasalized. China China
will be under intense pressure from the
US. That's how I see it.
Uh KLCC says, "What's up with silver
trade, China, US, UK angles?" I haven't
been paying attention to that. I have
been I I haven't been tracking the the
silver ups and downs the trade, so I
can't say. Sorry, I I'm I'm aware of
something going on, but I haven't really
been been tracking that. Yeah.
Duru bithorn says do you foresee a
possible future where it is advantageous
for the government to re reveal the
truth about subashindra and stop using
Gandhi India's go global branding yeah
once India becomes powerful that we
don't have to care about what the west
says and how the west demonizes us
that's when it could happen that you
know we could reveal the truth about
subashandra and stop using the branding
of Mahatma Gandhi Mr. Mahandas Gandhi
it's possible for that India will have
to become a much more powerful nation
minimum $10 trillion economy maybe more
maybe 10 20 perhaps 15 20 it's going to
happen in the future hopefully but for
that India needs significant
more hard power than what it is right
now
says based on what he just said about
North Korea isn't Israel fully sovereign
well that's that's a Great counter
argument. No question about that.
But Israel is fully sovereign.
[laughter]
That's all I can say. Because of the
amount of see
because of the amount of leverage it has
in the US. Let's just put it that way.
Okay? Let's just put it that way. Israel
is fully sovereign because of the amount
of leverage it has over the US.
internal leverage let's say all right
okay Arian Rajput says thank you for
this videos Jah Jah sir thank you so
much thank you Arig
lolha says why episodes on Friday these
days see when I travel I have the choice
of either not doing an an episode or
moving the episode around prefer to do
two episodes a week because I really
enjoy this
tomorrow I'm traveling so I thought
instead of canceling the episode I'll do
on Friday and that's why it's here
today. So today there's an episode and
there's an episode on Sunday but not
tomorrow.
Vir Kawat says is India now very likely
to get vasalized I think there is a high
probability but not 100% probability
maybe 60% probability but 40% no so I am
very hopeful despite the mathematical
difference of 60 over 40 I'm still very
hopeful that India will remain sovereign
I'm actually confident that India will
remain sovereign it's going to be a
tough road ahead for India
but yeah we're going uh prevail.
All right people, that brings me to the
end of today's live stream. Thank you
very much for all the questions. Really,
really fun, really interesting
geopolitics and history questions from
the comments and these live stream
questions as well. Thank you so much
everybody. Please keep learning. Keep
please keep asking questions. Please
keep raising your standards. I'll see
you in the Sunday live stream. Until
then, take care. See you soon.